<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Yuri Cunha]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Not just a DBA, but a data craftsman building digital legacies.]]></description>
        <link>https://localhost:3000</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 22:02:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://localhost:3000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 22:02:41 GMT</pubDate>
        <copyright><![CDATA[All rights reserved 2024, Yuri Cunha]]></copyright>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I was born in the wrong generation]]></title>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">I was born in the wrong generation</guid>
            <id>https://localhost:3000/blogs/i-was-born-in-the-wrong-generation</id>
            <updated>2024-03-20T22:55:00-03:00</updated>
            <description>Sometimes I feel like I was born in the wrong decade. I have principles that have already been lost and love things that are no longer valued.</description>
            <image>/static/images/blog/i-was-born-in-the-wrong-generation/i-was-born-in-the-wrong-generation.png</image>
            <content:encoded>
&lt;Image
  alt={
    &quot;Sometimes I feel like I was born in the wrong decade. I have principles that have already been lost and love things that are no longer valued.&quot;
  }
  src={&apos;/static/images/blog/i-was-born-in-the-wrong-generation/i-was-born-in-the-wrong-generation.png&apos;}
  width={1905 / 2}
  height={957 / 2}
  layout=&quot;responsive&quot;
  blurDataURL={
    &apos;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAQAAAACCAIAAADwyuo0AAAACXBIWXMAAA7EAAAOxAGVKw4bAAAAIklEQVQImWNgYBDnFZCxsfc0tvJkCI/O+vP/f0tdhZK8CgBLPAfARKUieAAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==&apos;
  }
  placeholder=&quot;blur&quot;
/&gt;

I think many people must have already read about how much I enjoy being alone, and for me, in a general context, it&apos;s okay, but I admit and confess: I wish I had someone.

You know, lately, during my aimless walks or in those moments when you start to ponder about life, I&apos;ve been thinking about how much I wish I had someone close to me. And when I say close, I mean a girlfriend.

It had become a sort of consensus that I would die alone, and when I say die alone, I mean without friends and a girl with whom I would or should share my life. Not that I see an extremely big problem here, but because, as I said, it was already a consensus.

I&apos;ve heard from my uncle that I would die like him, without friends, with a certain significant amount of money in the bank, but sad and happy at the same time. And the worst part is that I had already accepted that. I had really told myself many times, &quot;I&apos;m going to die alone and it&apos;s okay,&quot; and I really had in mind that it was okay. However, nowadays, despite it being okay and my acceptance of it, I really wish I had someone... But for me, it&apos;s extremely difficult to have or find someone.

I&apos;m a very logical guy and not very sentimental. I don&apos;t pretend or lie, I speak the truth straightforwardly, without beating around the bush. I don&apos;t measure the words I&apos;m going to say; there&apos;s no softening of the facts. I&apos;m also a guy with old moral values, so much so that there&apos;s a phrase I really like that says, &quot;Sometimes I feel like I was born in the wrong decade. I have principles that have been lost and love things that are no longer valued,&quot; and this is not even close to being a joke in good or bad taste.

I possess values ignored by many of the people I interact with today. And so I increasingly live with the conflict of feeling even more alone, even though I&apos;m surrounded by people who trivialize what I don&apos;t see as acceptable. Yes, I&apos;m also a romantic dude, and I don&apos;t see a problem with that. Yes, I miss when the little things were valued, and I have the right to reproduce and believe in what I find important but absent in our relationships.

I keep thinking about how crazy it would be to send a letter today to someone and know that the response will take a while to arrive. And that the response could come on a postcard with a photo along with a lipstick mark and the scent of that perfume that intoxicates as you read and gives that taste of presence. The truth is that we knew the importance of waiting, the effort it takes to cultivate a friendship or love relationship. We were aware of how difficult everything was to achieve, and so there was a greater sense of value. Today, some relationships begin and end, and people only got to know well the emojis used, the preferred poses in social media photos, the way the person uses ellipses and almost doesn&apos;t use commas. But they hardly knew the voice, hardly knew the emotions, hardly really looked into each other&apos;s eyes.

Today, many times, we find ourselves measuring the attention the other gives us by how quickly they view and respond to our messages. And if that message isn&apos;t answered, the war is declared, the confusion is armed. Because in the urgency we live in, we no longer know how to wait. It&apos;s the price we pay for living hurried days in our obligations, with virtual closeness and tremendous real distances.

In my parents&apos; and grandparents&apos; time, relationships actually ended. Today, they barely begin and often don&apos;t end. And just as it started in any casual chat, it ends with a nice ignore on WhatsApp, an unfollow on Twitter, and a thousand indirects on Instagram. Today, people live the cowardice of ending a relationship by SMS/WhatsApp and believe that a story can be subtly interrupted in a few characterless characters without much explanation, without showing the certainty of their decisions. It is indeed horrible to have to end something, but what&apos;s the reason for ending something so selfish and impartially? Discussing the relationship and the whole &quot;we need to talk&quot; thing has always been difficult. But I still prefer to look into each other&apos;s eyes, express my opinions, my dissatisfaction, hear the truth coming out of the person&apos;s mouth, even if I don&apos;t agree but knowing how to respect. And I think that&apos;s worth so much, but for many, it no longer means anything.

But it&apos;s sad how more and more nobody respects each other; there&apos;s no concern for anything beyond themselves. People live disrespecting one thing here and another there and begin to think it&apos;s normal and become one more to spread something that should be totally unacceptable. We live in a generation full of spoiled people. People who increasingly shirk their responsibilities. Who only want the good side of life but despair when they find themselves in difficulties. People who are great at living for one night but hardly know how to live for a month dedicated to someone. People who know very well what to say to convince someone to live some moments but don&apos;t know what to do to truly keep someone by their side. They want to live life urgently, with the tired speech that one must be happy and detached, waving the flag that one must experience all the pleasures of life. They believe the ends justify the means, even if they have to deceive, use people, pretend feelings, pretend to be someone they&apos;re not.

Whenever someone was going to do something for another, they should ask themselves: If it were me, how would I feel? Would I like it or hate it? Yes, you know I&apos;m indifferent about most things, but what I&apos;ve explained and many may not have understood, realized, or let pass is that I don&apos;t have antipathy; I just do my best not to create or get involved in others&apos; problems that are not directly related to me.

But the truth is that people seem to be getting used to wanting a lot while giving little. They believe everything should be temporary out of fear of outcomes, of attachments. Fear when the laughter ends, the table is no longer full, when there are no more jokes or good times. And so they live with each other as long as there&apos;s something to gain, to enjoy. As long as everything is good, as long as living is a good time. A mixture of selfishness with a high dose of interest. I think this explains the crowded bars and the empty rooms during hospital visits. This explains who abandons us when we need them the most.

But many, when reading this, may say that in our generation, despite these problems, everything has become easier. That now we don&apos;t call by phone or cell, but we use free internet calls and video conferences to do the same. But then I ask, how many really do that? The overwhelming majority content themselves with words because they are easily manipulable. Much can be said without caring about the truth, without caring about expressions, if they&apos;re laughing or not. If they&apos;re crying or not. Look around. People are together but glued to their cell phones. They&apos;re present but more concerned with taking photos to show off on social media. They waste the time they should be looking at each other, loving each other, enjoying the moment and the place, trying to find the best position to photograph and show how specialthat moment is. But if it truly were special, they wouldn&apos;t even think of capturing it. When something is truly unforgettable and we&apos;re busy enjoying it, we often forget to take many photos because listening to the other&apos;s voice, being present, kissing, hugging, enjoying is indeed the most important.

Before, to make a call, we had the cost of calling, it was a sacrifice. Receiving the call and hearing the &quot;Hello&quot; from that loved one was worthy of a declaration of love. It was really a proof that the person really missed us, cared, missed us. Before, we knew each other&apos;s handwriting, we spent a long time writing letters, flirting was much more fun. There was that moment of observing, exchanging glances. The other person was truly a mystery to us. We didn&apos;t know their tastes well because we hadn&apos;t stalked them on Instagram or Twitter/X before. Starting a conversation was somewhat intriguing, but it was more exciting because it was done in person, without much fuss. And to meet new people, we had to force ourselves out of our comfort zone and go out there to face the music. Today, the charm of a real conquest has been lost. Because it often starts to become quite rare. In other words, today everything is easily conquered, but also very easily discarded. We live in a programmed obsolescence among us.

Today people declare much more what they want, and because of that, there&apos;s not much conversation anymore, but just a little willingness from both, enough to do something at that moment. Today we have apps to get into a relationship. We choose people as if we were objects in a shop window. We&apos;re throwing away our inner values and fighting more and more to improve our exterior because in such superficial relationships, we don&apos;t have time to show anything else. What matters is always improving our beauty, camouflaging our age, and cultivating a few preferences and qualities as cliché as saying that we&apos;re perfectionists in a job interview. And right there we arrange a date, exchange a few words, and what used to take much longer and was more valued is now achieved very quickly and undervalued. It doesn&apos;t matter with whom, as long as in the end, we can have the maximum pleasure. That in the end, the night was worth it, to let off steam. Arrive, do it, make it happen, and leave.

And we keep living single, but in the illusion that we&apos;re never alone. We content ourselves with little when inside, we want much more, we want a lot. But we go on with life, accepting crumbs out of fear of loneliness. But perhaps what no one has noticed is that despite our choices, in the future beauty will have gone away, people will be even more accustomed to discarding, not valuing, only cultivating the superficial. Our destiny will be quite cruel because we&apos;ll see ourselves really as objects thrown away and that no one else wants. Because what remained in us, which should have been so important, was taught by ourselves to be trivialized. And yes, we&apos;ll be in complete loneliness. Still single, but we won&apos;t live in the illusion of being alone anymore; we&apos;ll be definitively abandoned.

And in the face of so much use of technology, we&apos;re becoming less real people, living virtual realities. We think that in life, everything must happen almost at the speed of light, at the speed of an email or a message through WhatsApp. We&apos;re accelerating things so much, lost in a hurry without any reason, when we should start relearning to live the moments more calmly. Relearn how important it is to value and have the other, have a friendship, a love.

The truth is that romantic relationships today last less because we&apos;re always racing off to experience everything as soon as possible. And they end because, obviously, everything happens so fast that it loses its charm. And today we don&apos;t try to fix anything, at the first defect or disappointment found, the person goes and calls the next in line of interested ones. We no longer make an effort for anything because before we see if it&apos;s real, we already surrender body and soul, with total recklessness in front of our self-love. And when someone feels entitled to go slower, many times the other doesn&apos;t understand, and finds themselves in a hurry to go live other stories that allow them to enjoy what is currently denied. But is that really important? Does it need to be like this? And what about those who use the pretext of trying to fill in the gaps of the relationship, resorting to betrayal? It&apos;s funny that people who cheat often don&apos;t want to be cheated on. In other words, they want everything for themselves and nothing for others. And we&apos;re increasingly losing ourselves in our desires.

And many go on like this, always justifying urgencies; everything is an emergency. The urgency is to live. But what does it really mean to live? Until when do we have to keep going in this frantic search to live only what&apos;s good? And when will we realize the value of the simplicity of life in the small moments? In the great efforts? When will we realize that life is not just pleasure, not just sex, and life is far from being this colorful world that people post about? When will we realize that we&apos;re losing ourselves in our freedoms? When will we learn that technologies help us to get closer, but physical proximity cannot be neglected? We must not stop looking into each other&apos;s eyes. We have to enjoy our advancements without devaluing what should never have gone out of style.

I hope people continue to realize that a smile is worth more than a &quot;=D&quot;. That a declaration of love made in person, a hug, sincere words, are worth more than a &quot;\&lt;3&quot; or a &quot;S2&quot;. I hope people don&apos;t replace the pleasant sound of the other&apos;s laughter with a fake &quot;hahahaha&quot; too much. We have to be close virtually, but even closer for a handshake. What we are on the outside is important, but what we have on the inside is much more impressive. Before hurting others, before using each other, discarding people like objects, we should never forget that inside each of us, there is a heart that, despite being hurt and disbelieved, only waits for the moment when it will truly be loved for who it really is. We don&apos;t just want a message viewed and responded to; we want to be seen and reciprocated. Let us continue living our lives hurriedly, very committed, but knowing how to value the sweet taste of waiting, lived without fear. May we learn to prune the freedoms that can distance us from ourselves. Life was made to be and not to have. Let&apos;s never lose ourselves in our daydreams, let&apos;s never stop being who we really are. We must not let ourselves be trapped by the other&apos;s reckless freedom. We deserve love, we deserve more calmness, more respect. We deserve to live slower. Whoever is in a hurry can go ahead; in the end, we&apos;ll all be in the same place.

Ah, indeed, I&apos;m in the wrong generation.

Today, I&apos;ll end it here.
Take care. Love each other. And I hope you find that person who will love you and be with you until the end of your life, and every time you look at each other, your eyes shine mutually.

This time, I&apos;ll end with the following closing and greeting:
With love, Yuri.</content:encoded>
            <author>
                <name>yuricunha</name>
                <email>hidden</email>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Work, Travel, Cultures & Decisions]]></title>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">Work, Travel, Cultures &amp; Decisions</guid>
            <id>https://localhost:3000/blogs/work-travel-cultures-decisions</id>
            <updated>2024-03-03T18:20:00-03:00</updated>
            <description>Exploring work, travel, cultural encounters, and personal decisions.</description>
            <image>/static/images/blog/work-travel-cultures-decisions/work-travel-cultures-decisions.png</image>
            <content:encoded>
&lt;Image
  alt={
    &quot;Exploring work, travel, cultural encounters, and personal decisions.&quot;
  }
  src={&apos;/static/images/blog/work-travel-cultures-decisions/work-travel-cultures-decisions.png&apos;}
  width={1905 / 2}
  height={957 / 2}
  layout=&quot;responsive&quot;
  blurDataURL={
    &apos;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAQAAAACCAIAAADwyuo0AAAACXBIWXMAAA7EAAAOxAGVKw4bAAAAIklEQVQImWNgYBDnFZCxsfc0tvJkCI/O+vP/f0tdhZK8CgBLPAfARKUieAAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==&apos;
  }
  placeholder=&quot;blur&quot;
/&gt;

This week I had several ideas about what to post, but none of them seemed reasonable enough to share here, and as you know, this blog doesn&apos;t have a posting &quot;schedule&quot;... I post when I want to.

As some people know, I design, set up, and maintain databases, which is just my main job. There&apos;s also the fact that I set up servers, from hardware to cabling and configurations - and there are smaller gigs like freelance website development and volunteering as a math and artificial intelligence teacher for children. So, I end up traveling for various jobs, and currently, I&apos;ve been to Canada, Japan, China, the United States, and France. Sometimes, during these trips, I end up extending my stay in the country (nothing that would expire my visa).

So, every time I extend my time in the countries I visit, I end up using the right part (brain analytics) and observing the details of each culture, and the more I see, the happier I am to know new cultures, and I use this to improve myself. And, I believe the coolest culture I&apos;ve encountered was the Japanese, and I say this in a general life context.

The Japanese, in their majority, have a culture of striving to be better, giving their best, and not disrespecting people. That&apos;s something I find really cool.

It&apos;s very rare to see a Japanese person doing something to bring shame upon themselves or their close ones, and when I say close ones, I mean friends, family, and even professional hierarchy. Even politicians who steal usually commit seppuku (suicide) for having brought shame to their own family name. It&apos;s sad but highly courageous, seriously.

In Japan, for the most part, you see boys trying to have a considerably more comfortable and stable life so that they have the ability to start and maintain a family. Of course, there&apos;s also the issue of girls, who for the most part, try to minimize exposure of their bodies both virtually and physically (no, they don&apos;t wear sweatshirts when they go to the beach in the summer), the way they learn to sit in the seiza style (although it can be somewhat painful), and how they behave in general in front of people, like giving themselves respect.

Of course, not everything is rosy, but their culture manages to be better than all the others in my opinion (and certainly much better than the current one in my country, Brazil).

You need to see, within their own home, you use soft slippers only indoors, and when you go to someone else&apos;s house, known or not, if you enter it, you can&apos;t just walk in with your shoes on... they will give you one of those soft slippers they keep for visitors to use. Another extremely strong point is that you don&apos;t see Japanese people coming into your home and going after you, that doesn&apos;t exist... first, you&apos;re invited in, and then, after being invited, your limit is the person&apos;s living room, but that&apos;s the extent of how far you go, meaning they won&apos;t go and wander around your house, and now comes another cool point: you/they cannot sit without the resident&apos;s permission. Isn&apos;t that cool? They come to your house, you sit down, and if they don&apos;t say &quot;dozo&quot; (&quot;go ahead&quot;), they&apos;ll stand because without your permission, it becomes disrespectful.

Bowing to someone and/or when apologizing is cool... you show that you made a mistake, and in your mistake, you were disrespectful.

Calling someone by their family name, in respect to them and their family, is another thing that I consider incredibly amazing, seriously.

To be honest, if it weren&apos;t for my flawed Japanese (which I&apos;m already studying and will be my fourth language), I would try for a resident visa.

Maybe another culture that I find interesting is Canada&apos;s, where you can see French and English (British-French with a bit of American) traits, so much so that you can see places like Quebec, where they mix French with English, but that will be (with a big maybe) for another post here on the blog.

Changing the subject, moving away from work, travel, and cultures, lately, I&apos;ve decided to try new things, like getting on Tinder to meet someone interesting - and what I can say sincerely about it is that if you&apos;re looking for something carnal/casual/sexual, you can go ahead without fear because you&apos;ll find plenty. There was a time between 2017 and 2021 when Tinder was good, its design was more traditional (rustic and exotic), and you didn&apos;t have to pay to have a friendly/nice experience on it, but now, most of the reports I&apos;ve heard say that you &quot;need&quot; to pay, otherwise, you won&apos;t get matches, won&apos;t be seen by other people, and a bunch of other things... I personally haven&apos;t tried this &quot;free-paid&quot; Tinder because I have a partnership with them, so I have a monthly code renewed with gold for free... in a week on Tinder, I had an average of 200 matches, and let&apos;s be honest, I&apos;m not a handsome guy, actually, according to a survey (and there was one), with 25 consulted girls, on a scale of 0 to 10 (0 being horrible and 10 being a dream guy), I got 8.25, which is a high average.

On Tinder, I would select the people I liked the most by their bio (yes, I read all the bios), and those who didn&apos;t have one or only put their Instagram username, I would select based on visual appeal. And what you might say is &quot;wow, that&apos;s hypocritical,&quot; I don&apos;t believe it is, because I don&apos;t buy clothes that don&apos;t appeal to me visually (although most are black or dark blue and plain). But, honestly, most people there were too superficial. When I saw someone saying they liked &quot;Game of Thrones&quot; books, I would ask or mention something about &quot;A Song of Ice and Fire,&quot; the person didn&apos;t even know which book it was. Or when they were fans of hardware or big geeks, and the person only talked to me about a super-fast computer or Naruto and that&apos;s it... mediocre subject, with the person most of the time not leaving space for a question or continuation of the conversation. But, for me, the worst people were the ones who, in the first message, would send you their phone number, or Instagram username, and then add &quot;I don&apos;t come here much&quot;... so I deleted the account. Besides, Tinder&apos;s guidelines say you can&apos;t put your Instagram in the bio, in fact, it mentions that you can&apos;t put any form of external contact in your profile (I even reported some for this), and there were people selling packs, like onlyfans directly in the bio, or who would message you asking for your number or Instagram username, so when they call you, they&apos;d start with a generic message, followed by an image with the prices of nude packs... sad.

When I was younger, I really wanted to have a girlfriend, start a serious relationship and develop that, but at the height of my 19/20 years, that desire died directly, and I kept that idea calmly until a friend said &quot;try again, it&apos;s worth it,&quot; so I listened to my best friend, just to refute his thesis with something recent... I chose Tinder because I

 wasn&apos;t aware of this &quot;menu for intercourse/coitus&quot;, and I refuted him. But he didn&apos;t accept it, so I started going out with friends to social events, and I met eight girls, six of them wanted only sexual/casual relationships, and two wanted only a &quot;friend with benefits&quot;, so I avoided them. Once again, as a trained physicist that I am, I presented my thesis to him, and then he accepted it.

Honestly, I&apos;m not the type to succumb to this kind of &quot;peer pressure&quot; because I only have three friends, and we three are what I can call &quot;unethical,&quot; we reject many of the standards that society imposes nowadays.

In conclusion, I went back to my MGTOW (men going their own way).

Although I&apos;ve been in MGTOW since I was 19/20 years old, I don&apos;t feel a lack or need to be with someone daily... of course, I sometimes miss cuddling, but I don&apos;t miss (missing and longing are different things, research), but when I think that nowadays, everyone is hooking up with everyone, and that people don&apos;t have any culture anymore, even though they&apos;re educated (culture and education are different things, research, but, in short, culture is how you behave, education is your educational ability, like reading and writing).

Another decision I made was to treat people outside my circle with complete indifference, like, before, I still tried to treat people I was talking to as a possible person I would have in my life in the future, nowadays, I&apos;ve decided not to do that anymore, it&apos;s exhausting, and although it might not seem different, but when you&apos;re someone I consider from my circle (and even a large part of my family isn&apos;t), I&apos;m completely different... I randomly text, send some cool articles, invite you to go out on the weekend, to travel with me, send you gifts, and even text as if I didn&apos;t know how to write anymore, all stupidly, and even send you photos like a goofball.

But, closing this article/post, what I&apos;ve decided most recently is that I won&apos;t do any more experiments that will require me to try to find someone to share life with... I&apos;ll comfortably stay in my MGTOW &amp; my eternal solitude, and finally, I&apos;ll adhere to a relationship solely and exclusively casual/carnal/sexual.

Take care.</content:encoded>
            <author>
                <name>yuricunha</name>
                <email>hidden</email>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[One month after leaving the internet and leaving everyone believing I'm still active]]></title>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">One month after leaving the internet and leaving everyone believing I&apos;m still active</guid>
            <id>https://localhost:3000/blogs/one-month-after-leaving-the-internet-and-leaving-everyone-believing-im-still-active</id>
            <updated>2024-02-16T21:15:00-03:00</updated>
            <description>I left social media, left my bots and AIs pretending I&apos;m still there, and have been smiling more offline.</description>
            <image>/static/images/blog/one-month-after-leaving-the-internet-and-leaving-everyone-believing-im-still-active/one-month-after-leaving-the-internet-and-leaving-everyone-believing-im-still-active.jpg</image>
            <content:encoded>
&lt;Image
  alt={
    &quot;I left social media, left my bots and AIs pretending I&apos;m still there, and have been smiling more offline.&quot;
  }
  src={&apos;/static/images/blog/one-month-after-leaving-the-internet-and-leaving-everyone-believing-im-still-active/one-month-after-leaving-the-internet-and-leaving-everyone-believing-im-still-active.jpg&apos;}
  width={1905 / 2}
  height={957 / 2}
  layout=&quot;responsive&quot;
  blurDataURL={
    &apos;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAQAAAACCAIAAADwyuo0AAAACXBIWXMAAA7EAAAOxAGVKw4bAAAAIklEQVQImWNgYBDnFZCxsfc0tvJkCI/O+vP/f0tdhZK8CgBLPAfARKUieAAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==&apos;
  }
  placeholder=&quot;blur&quot;
/&gt;

It&apos;s been...a month since I left social media.

I said in my previous post that I would delete my social media accounts, but then I did something better: I activated my AIs, my bots, and automated my posts. So, sometimes I post something through my private bot on Telegram. It formats and adds things using Tailwind patterns.

My bot sees some posts, likes others, and does what I used to do but have no desire to do anymore: look at what other people are doing.

How do I feel off social media?

Well, I feel great.

I thought I would go through a social media detox, but it seems that it wasn&apos;t even necessary. I don&apos;t open Instagram, Twitter, or Snapchat to see if anyone sent me something, much less do I check from time to time if someone posted something new, whether it&apos;s someone I&apos;m following or someone I like to see (like Yetz).

Personally, I&apos;m much better than I was before.

My solitude and mindfulness practices have improved significantly. My phone usage has decreased from 1.5 to 2 hours to just 25 to 30 minutes. This has been incredibly beneficial.

Currently, my daily activities consist of listening to music on my headphones, responding to messages from my few friends, and occasionally checking Tinder to see what&apos;s up.

The only exception to my phone usage meter is my Kindle. I don&apos;t see the need to own a separate Kindle e-book reader. When I&apos;m out and about, if I&apos;m not reading a physical book or an e-book on my phone, I&apos;m playing games on my PSP (PlayStation Portable), especially on long trips or when I&apos;m not in the mood to read.

Shifting gears slightly, but staying on the topic, I&apos;m much happier and more at peace with myself.

My friends used to call me a &quot;weird nerd,&quot; not in a derogatory sense, but because I have a resting &quot;bad boy&quot; face and always seem angry or like I don&apos;t want to talk to anyone. In reality, I&apos;m just a nerdy guy who loves manga, books, anime, and technology. To top it off, I&apos;m low-key and rarely post anything on the internet (my bot does it for me). I only view things I&apos;m tagged or mentioned in, which is quite often.

I&apos;ve always been a fan of my solitude. I only post things that have already happened in my life, so many of my posts are recycled. My AI-powered bot learned this and now replicates it, which makes some people think I&apos;m out having fun with friends when I&apos;m actually just reading a book, chatting with friends on Discord, or playing games on my computer, PlayStation, or PSP.

Every day, I go for a morning walk or run, complete my work tasks, and read something. I&apos;m currently reading &quot;The Hedge Knight&quot; by George R.R. Martin, which is set in the same world as &quot;A Song of Ice and Fire&quot; (the Game of Thrones series), but the story takes place before that time period. When I&apos;m not reading, I enjoy taking leisurely walks or runs of 10-15 kilometers around my city.

On one of my random walks around, I found one or two people who were sad and I made them smile, but the point is, I usually make people think a lot about life.

Just this week, I met a girl walking, and I was walking in the same direction, but I was walking fast, so I was faster than her. When I stopped at the crosswalk, I noticed with my peripheral vision that she was looking at me, so I looked at her, smiled, and she smiled back. I took out my headphones and said, &quot;Every day I like to make someone smile, after all, a day without smiles is a day wasted.&quot; She laughed and said that day was not a wasted day. I laughed lovingly at that phrase and told her to take care, put my headphones back on and started walking again.

On the way I found a St. Bernard dog (the same name as my city) and I always thought this breed was wonderful, so I had to stop to pet the dog. I thanked the owner for letting me pet the dog and continued on my way. After that I arrived at the Green Area square (the people in my city gave this nickname to the square, but it has another name). I bought an acai, sat on an isolated wooden bench, and listened to some Post Malone songs, while watching people walking, running or exercising, and said to myself &quot;if I was wasting my time on social networks, I wouldn&apos;t be able to have smiled as much as I smiled today.&quot;

Ah, each day has been wonderful and unique, even if I do repetitive things, these things end up becoming unique because of something that happens while I&apos;m doing that task.

I believe the craziest part of this is that I am doing many things without losing my solitude. I never looked for validation on social media, just as I never cared if people stopped talking to me. Seriously, I&apos;m the kind of guy that most girls would be angry with, because if I send you a message and you ignore me on purpose, I don&apos;t care. If I send you a message and you don&apos;t answer me for days, I won&apos;t send another message asking for attention, time or an answer. I always answer whenever I pick up my cell phone, so if you take a minute or ten days to answer me, when I pick up my cell phone or open Telegram or WhatsApp on my computer, I will answer you.

Many people think that my way of being is because I don&apos;t care, and that&apos;s not quite right. Although I love my solitude, if I have a relationship with you, whether friendly or romantic, and you take a long time to show up, I will call to see if you are okay. If you don&apos;t answer, I will send you a text message or a message through an app. The problem is that it takes time for you to become my friend, but when that happens, you become part of my lived routine.

There is a big difference between when you are just a person who talks to me and when you become at least a person with a relationship that I consider a friendship. And probably the biggest difference is that I will show and talk much more than if you weren&apos;t.

Now, speaking of this blog, it is my day-to-day or what I like to call my &quot;time-to-time&quot;, because I post here when I believe there will be a post, and it is not linear, quite the contrary.

Well, today I will end this post here.

Always remember that you can send me an email or call me on Telegram.

Take care.</content:encoded>
            <author>
                <name>yuricunha</name>
                <email>hidden</email>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My last goodbye]]></title>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">My last goodbye</guid>
            <id>https://localhost:3000/blogs/my-last-goodbye</id>
            <updated>2024-01-16T09:15:00-03:00</updated>
            <description>It&apos;s finally time to say goodbye to social media, and it took a while.</description>
            <image>/static/images/blog/my-last-goodbye/my-last-goodbye.jpg</image>
            <content:encoded>
&lt;Image
  alt={
    &quot;It&apos;s finally time to say goodbye to social media, and it took a while.&quot;
  }
  src={&apos;/static/images/blog/my-last-goodbye/my-last-goodbye.jpg&apos;}
  width={1905 / 2}
  height={957 / 2}
  layout=&quot;responsive&quot;
  blurDataURL={
    &apos;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAQAAAACCAIAAADwyuo0AAAACXBIWXMAAA7EAAAOxAGVKw4bAAAAIklEQVQImWNgYBDnFZCxsfc0tvJkCI/O+vP/f0tdhZK8CgBLPAfARKUieAAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==&apos;
  }
  placeholder=&quot;blur&quot;
/&gt;

In the midst of this era defined by relentless connectivity, I stand at the crossroads of an extraordinary digital transformation, contemplating a pivotal decision that will redefine my relationship with the virtual realm. Today signifies the commencement of a profound chapter—the deliberate erasure of my social media footprint. Instagram, Facebook, Twitter, Snapchat, and various other platforms that once dictated my online existence are now on the brink of extinction in my digital universe. In this odyssey, I&apos;m not merely bidding farewell to virtual connections; I&apos;m dismantling the intricate web of automation that once orchestrated my online narrative.

Imagine this: my Instagram, once a meticulously curated gallery of automated reposts imitating the influencer Yetz, is now dissipating into the vast digital abyss. The seamless replication of Yetz&apos;s Instagram stories, orchestrated by bots and AI, is gracefully coming to a halt. This departure signifies more than just a retreat from artificial glamour; it marks a profound shift from the borrowed shine of someone else&apos;s life.

My inner circle, ever adaptive, has already transitioned to alternative communication platforms such as Signal, Session, or Telegram to stay connected. Nevertheless, the impending solitude prompts a self-imposed digital retreat. My phone, now permanently set in &apos;Do Not Disturb&apos; mode and cloaked in grayscale, imposes strict limits on the time allocated to each application—a mere 25 minutes per day. Farewell, Facebook, Instagram, and Snapchat; a new chapter begins.

The decision to sever ties with social media is deeply rooted in a profound realization: the reasons to disconnect far outweigh those compelling me to stay linked. The tipping point was a seemingly idyllic Instagram post showcasing a picturesque sunset, concealing the underlying truth of that moment—I was battling subtle depression, hungry and cold. Why did I feel the need to showcase a facade of perfection when authenticity was my true essence?

To aid in this transformative endeavor, I&apos;ve armed myself with an arsenal of tools and strategies:

### On my computer:
- News Feed Eradicator
- Distraction-free YouTube extension

### On my phone:
- Grayscale display
- Airplane mode
- Focus modes, particularly &apos;Do Not Disturb&apos;
- App-specific time limits

### In cultivating healthy habits:
- Meditation heightens self-awareness, curbing impulsive behaviors.
- Reading replaces mindless scrolling, enhancing attention span.
- Musical instruments and sports fill the void with gratifying activities.

### Various lifestyle changes:
- A physical alarm clock keeps my phone in a separate room, deterring late-night or early-morning digital temptations.
- A &apos;dumb&apos; watch replaces my Fitbit, reducing dependency on constant notifications.
- A notebook and pen capture fleeting thoughts, replacing digital clutter.
- Kindle or physical books offer an escape from the digital world.
- Letter writing with envelopes and stamps resurrects the charm of traditional correspondence.
- Venturing outside, I intentionally leave my phone behind or stow it away in a bag. The more I distance myself, the more I realize how little I truly need it.

In the pursuit of disconnection, I find solace in silence—a sanctuary away from the curated noise of social media. This intentional withdrawal is a quest to rediscover authenticity, rebuild meaningful connections, and savor the beauty of life without the digital filter.

As the days unfold in my journey of digital emancipation, the void left by the absence of constant notifications and virtual validations begins to fill with a profound sense of clarity. The quiet moments, once drowned out by the incessant buzz of likes and comments, now echo with the subtle melody of my own thoughts. The deliberate steps I&apos;ve taken to minimize my digital presence are slowly transforming into a dance of liberation, a choreography of rediscovery.

With each passing sunrise, I witness the world with unfiltered eyes, unencumbered by the virtual lens that once colored my perceptions. The hues of the sky, the rustle of leaves, and the laughter of strangers in a coffee shop all become more vibrant, more authentic, as if the world has shed its pixelated veil. This newfound clarity extends beyond the physical realm, penetrating the depths of my relationships.

I begin to appreciate the genuine conversations that flourish without the constant interruption of notification pings. The richness of a shared moment, unmarred by the compulsion to document it for online consumption, adds a layer of authenticity to my interactions. As I delve into the art of letter writing, the tactile pleasure of putting pen to paper becomes a sensory experience, replacing the sterile tap of a keyboard.

The digital detox seeps into my professional life, too, as I reevaluate the meaning of productivity in a world perpetually connected. The once incessant urge to check emails and respond to Slack messages is replaced by a deliberate focus on deep work. My creative pursuits, once overshadowed by the instant gratification of social media engagement, now unfold in the quiet sanctuary of concentration.

Yet, the process of disconnecting is not without its challenges. The reflex to reach for my phone in idle moments, seeking the instant distraction of a digital scroll, remains a persistent echo of my former self. However, armed with resilience, I redirect that impulse towards more mindful activities – a few pages of a captivating novel, a stroll in the park, or a moment of quiet reflection.

The absence of curated perfection in my virtual life accentuates the beauty of imperfection in the real world. I embrace the candid snapshots of life, acknowledging the rawness of emotions and the unpredictability of experiences. The flaws and vulnerabilities once concealed behind filters now stand proudly, adding depth to the tapestry of my existence.

As I navigate this uncharted territory, I find myself becoming an unintentional advocate for a life less digitally adorned. Friends and acquaintances, initially perplexed by my decision, begin to witness the transformative effects. Some join me in the pursuit of mindful disconnection, while others observe from a distance, curious about the path less traveled.

In the quietude of this digital detox, I forge a deeper connection with myself. The introspective moments that were once fleeting now become a constant companion. In the absence of external validations, I discover an internal compass guiding me towards authenticity and self-discovery.

With each passing chapter of this narrative, the decision to sever ties with the digital mirage emerges as a pivotal turning point. The canvas of my life, once crowded with pixelated imitations, now awaits the strokes of genuine experiences and unfiltered emotions. The odyssey continues, and as I navigate the uncharted waters of a life less connected, I realize that in disconnecting from the virtual noise, I&apos;m uncovering the symphony of my true self.</content:encoded>
            <author>
                <name>yuricunha</name>
                <email>hidden</email>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Embracing Feelings Amidst Indifference]]></title>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">Embracing Feelings Amidst Indifference</guid>
            <id>https://localhost:3000/blogs/embracing-feelings-indifference</id>
            <updated>2023-12-29T18:40:00-03:00</updated>
            <description>I&apos;m feeling indifferent about a lot of things, and it&apos;s okay.</description>
            <image>/static/images/blog/embracing-feelings-indifference/embracing-feelings-indifference.png</image>
            <content:encoded>
&lt;Image
  alt={
    &quot;Indif..&quot;
  }
  src={&apos;/static/images/blog/embracing-feelings-indifference/embracing-feelings-indifference.png&apos;}
  width={1905 / 2}
  height={957 / 2}
  layout=&quot;responsive&quot;
  blurDataURL={
    &apos;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAQAAAACCAIAAADwyuo0AAAACXBIWXMAAA7EAAAOxAGVKw4bAAAAIklEQVQImWNgYBDnFZCxsfc0tvJkCI/O+vP/f0tdhZK8CgBLPAfARKUieAAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==&apos;
  }
  placeholder=&quot;blur&quot;
/&gt;

As the seasons changed and time marched on, my unique approach to life continued to shape my interactions. I found solace in the simplicity of my indifference, but it also became a dividing line between me and those who struggled to comprehend my perspective.

One day, I found myself at the center of an unexpected situation that tested the limits of my apathy. A colleague, Maria, approached me with tears in her eyes. She had just experienced a devastating breakup and sought comfort in the presence of a friend.

&quot;Yuri,&quot; she whispered, her voice trembling, &quot;I don&apos;t know what to do. He left me, and I feel like my world is falling apart.&quot;

I glanced at her, my expression unmoved. It wasn&apos;t that I lacked empathy; it was simply that I couldn&apos;t fathom investing emotional energy in the melodrama of someone else&apos;s failed relationship.

&quot;Maria,&quot; I replied calmly, &quot;breakups are tough, but life goes on. You&apos;ll get through this, just like countless others have. Don&apos;t let a failed relationship define your happiness.&quot;

Her tearful eyes met mine, searching for a glimmer of understanding. Finding none, she shook her head in disbelief. &quot;Yuri, I thought you were my friend. How can you be so cold?&quot;

I sighed, recognizing that not everyone could appreciate the simplicity of my indifference. &quot;Maria, I can be your friend, but I won&apos;t indulge in unnecessary emotional turmoil. If you need practical advice or a distraction, I&apos;m here. But I won&apos;t wallow in your emotions with you.&quot;

As Maria walked away, her disappointment lingered in the air. It was a reminder that my approach to relationships was a double-edged sword—one that cut through unnecessary drama but also left others wounded by the absence of expected empathy.

Amidst the ebb and flow of my unconventional interactions, I found a surprising ally in an acquaintance named James. He, too, had embraced a similar philosophy of detachment, finding comfort in the simplicity of not caring about societal expectations.

James and I often sat in the park, observing the world with a shared sense of detachment. We laughed at the trivialities that consumed the lives of those around us—people stressing over inconsequential matters, societal norms dictating behavior, and the relentless pursuit of validation.

&quot;You know, Yuri,&quot; James said with a chuckle, &quot;not caring is liberating. We&apos;re free from the chains that bind others, the need to conform and fit into molds that society creates.&quot;

I nodded in agreement, appreciating the camaraderie in our shared indifference. In a world where everyone seemed to be chasing after something, James and I found contentment in the pursuit of nothing.

The Evolution of Indifference

As the years passed, I noticed a subtle evolution in my attitude toward indifference. It wasn&apos;t merely a shield against the trivialities of life; it became a guiding principle for navigating the complexities of relationships and personal growth.

I met Emily, a fellow enthusiast of solitude and introspection. Our connection was built on shared silences, comfortable in the absence of unnecessary words. Together, we explored the beauty of nonchalance, weaving a tapestry of understanding that transcended the need for constant validation.

Emily and I chose a life less ordinary, free from the burdens of societal expectations. We traveled to distant lands, explored the depths of our passions, and reveled in the simplicity of just being. Our bond thrived in the space between words, where actions spoke louder than empty promises.

Yet, even in the sanctuary of our shared indifference, challenges arose. Emily faced a critical decision regarding her career, torn between the expectations of her family and the pursuit of her true passions.

&quot;Yuri,&quot; she confided in me, &quot;I don&apos;t want to succumb to the pressures and expectations, but the weight of familial obligations is suffocating.&quot;

I gazed into her eyes, acknowledging the gravity of her dilemma. In that moment, I realized that my indifference had evolved into a source of strength, a foundation upon which genuine connections could flourish.

&quot;Emily,&quot; I said with a sincerity that transcended my usual bluntness, &quot;don&apos;t let the expectations of others dictate your path. You have the power to shape your destiny. If they truly care about you, they&apos;ll understand. If not, their opinions shouldn&apos;t weigh you down.&quot;

She nodded, a glimmer of determination in her eyes. Emily embraced the power of indifference, not as a shield against the world but as a catalyst for personal growth and authentic connections.

The Ripple Effect

In the wake of my journey through the landscape of indifference, I began to notice a ripple effect in the lives of those around me. Some embraced the concept, finding liberation in shedding the unnecessary baggage of societal expectations. Others recoiled, unable to grasp the nuances of a life unburdened by the need for constant validation.

A close friend, Daniel, approached me one day with a perplexed expression. &quot;Yuri, I&apos;ve been watching how you navigate life with this indifference, and I can&apos;t wrap my head around it. Doesn&apos;t it get lonely?&quot;

I chuckled, realizing that my path wasn&apos;t for everyone. &quot;Daniel, indifference isn&apos;t about loneliness; it&apos;s about freedom. I choose my connections wisely, investing in relationships that matter rather than spreading myself thin trying to please everyone. It&apos;s a conscious choice, not a result of isolation.&quot;

As Daniel mulled over my words, I couldn&apos;t help but reflect on the journey that led me to this point. Indifference, once a shield against the noise of the world, had become a guiding principle—a philosophy that shaped not only my life but the lives of those willing to explore its depths.

In the grand tapestry of existence, my story unfolded as a testament to the power of embracing one&apos;s true self. It was a narrative of authenticity, resilience, and the unyielding pursuit of a life well-lived.

And so, as I penned the final words of my tale, I couldn&apos;t help but marvel at the intricate dance of indifference that had propelled me forward. In a world saturated with noise, I had found harmony in the simplicity of not caring about most things, allowing the symphony of my existence to play on, unhindered and true to its unique melody.

Among the pages of my diary of indifference, there were still unwritten chapters, nuances that challenged the apparent coldness of my philosophy. Despite the aura of detachment permeating my existence, I was not immune to the emotional echoes reverberating in the trenches of my being.

On a serene night, as the stars drew constellations in the sky, a nostalgic melody echoed in the air. It was a song that awakened memories buried beneath the layers of my indifference. I felt a twinge of longing, a distant echo of feelings I had carefully stored away.

I received a message from someone from the past, someone who once shared laughter and secrets with me. Their words were an invitation to reminisce about times the clock had forgotten. I accepted the invitation, not due to a sudden wave of emotion, but out of curiosity to explore the forgotten corners of my own heart.

Our meeting was like a journey through time, a dive into the deep waters of memory. We laughed at old jokes, revisited places that were once silent witnesses to our joys and sorrows. Although I remained true to my philosophy of indifference, a gentle flame of nostalgia burned beneath the surface.

Amidst shared stories and meaningful glances, I realized that my indifference did not make me immune to the beauty of lived moments. There was still room for appreciating the subtleties of life, for the warmth of a rekindled friendship.

Even though I presented myself as an architect of indifference, shaping my world with straight lines of rationality, the truth lay in the complexity of emotions pulsating within me. I was, after all, human. A man with a heart that, though guarded by layers of indifference, still vibrated to the touch of genuine emotions.

This experience did not fundamentally alter my approach to life, but it left an indelible mark. There were still fragments of sensitivity that, even under the armor of indifference, pulsated with a unique resonance.

And so, with the renewed knowledge that my journey through indifference had not turned me into an imperturbable statue, I continued to walk the paths of life. With each step, I acknowledged the duality of my existence: the pursuit of clarity through indifference and the constant reminder that, even in pages written with the ink of apathy, the heart still echoed its silent melodies.</content:encoded>
            <author>
                <name>yuricunha</name>
                <email>hidden</email>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Disconnected]]></title>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">Disconnected</guid>
            <id>https://localhost:3000/blogs/disconnected</id>
            <updated>2023-12-17T10:20:00-03:00</updated>
            <description>Chillin&apos; offline, dodging memes, and loving real-life adventures!</description>
            <image>/static/images/blog/disconnected/disconnected.jpg</image>
            <content:encoded>
&lt;Image
  alt={
    &quot;Disconnected.&quot;
  }
  src={&apos;/static/images/blog/disconnected/disconnected.jpg&apos;}
  width={1905 / 2}
  height={957 / 2}
  layout=&quot;responsive&quot;
  blurDataURL={
    &apos;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAQAAAACCAIAAADwyuo0AAAACXBIWXMAAA7EAAAOxAGVKw4bAAAAIklEQVQImWNgYBDnFZCxsfc0tvJkCI/O+vP/f0tdhZK8CgBLPAfARKUieAAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==&apos;
  }
  placeholder=&quot;blur&quot;
/&gt;

I currently find myself disinterested in consuming online content and engaging with online communities, but it doesn&apos;t feel bad at all. It was not spurred by anything negative I encountered; it just happened. It feels more like a phase I need right now or potentially permanently growing out of certain internet habits.

I don&apos;t have Facebook, Instagram, Threads, X, Reddit, Tumblr, YouTube, Mastodon, Bluesky, or TikTok accounts. I usually come across funny memes or videos through friends who send them to me. I am on a few small, friends-only Discord servers that move slowly and don&apos;t generate any fear of missing out, keeping me undistracted. Even then, I recently noticed I don&apos;t care to properly look at the latest Tumblr post screenshot or meme and just move past it. When I check HackerNews or Tildes, I spend at most 5-10 minutes on them. Many times when I open those websites, I end up closing them almost immediately without clicking anything. The few YouTube channels I watch tend to upload about once a month, and I check them manually every now and then.

There were times when I was excited about new communities popping up or discovering new niches of the internet, lurking on them or trying them out, especially around the small web. But right now, I feel comfortable being offline a lot, proceeding with my own little projects at my own pace, working on myself, and having a good time with people in real life. I don&apos;t feel pressured to keep my online identity up. My website has been reworked since October, but I no longer feel the need to do it as fast as possible or to have something flashy and new to present, like a finished project or progress in my learning. Everything is happening without the pressure to perform or put something online.

Earlier, I came across some other online communities and wondered if it was something worth engaging in, something to sign up for, check, and get to know, like I used to do. However, I embrace the digital reduction and partial digital solitude. I have already announced plans to step down from some community I spent a lot of time on to focus on other things in January. Instead, I will be more creative with my art, continue embroidery projects, study for my degree, read some books, meet new people, restart The Odin Project, and learn more Rust. I love the view of my laptop as this personal project machine that also has messages from my friends and some games, and nothing else.

I see others going through a similar thing, like a disillusionment with how they usually use the internet, which is amazing. I hope you all find the niche communities you crave and curate the RSS feed of your dreams. Mine is best left empty right now.


&lt;Aside type={&apos;positive&apos;} title={&apos;Thank you very much for reading!&apos;}&gt;
  Well, if you&apos;d like, you can listen to this text/post. I have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/show/2XRQ2mpUbtT0ZqxFVrl0KK&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; where I read my posts out loud. It&apos;s called &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/show/2XRQ2mpUbtT0ZqxFVrl0KK&quot;&gt;Yuri Cunha - Blog Speech&lt;/a&gt; and it&apos;s available on Spotify, Google Podcasts, and Anchor. This post is &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/episode/5vRjCOijzce9ChR6H9KdAR?si=4ef5e07e900648fd&quot;&gt;right here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/Aside&gt;</content:encoded>
            <author>
                <name>yuricunha</name>
                <email>hidden</email>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sometimes Humans Just Need to Sit in One Place and, Like, Hurt]]></title>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">Sometimes Humans Just Need to Sit in One Place and, Like, Hurt</guid>
            <id>https://localhost:3000/blogs/sometimes-humans-just-need-to-sit-in-one-place-and-like-hurt</id>
            <updated>2023-12-02T01:15:00-03:00</updated>
            <description>Reflecting on life&apos;s twists, from betrayal to forging connections. Embracing pain, trust&apos;s evolution, and adulting challenges. Candidly exploring personal growth, writing, and venturing into coaching with a resilient spirit.</description>
            <image>/static/images/blog/sometimes-humans-just-need-to-sit-in-one-place-and-like-hurt/sit-and-hurt.gif</image>
            <content:encoded>
&lt;Image
  alt={
    &quot;Reflecting on life&apos;s twists, from betrayal to forging connections. Embracing pain, trust&apos;s evolution, and adulting challenges. Candidly exploring personal growth, writing, and venturing into coaching with a resilient spirit.&quot;
  }
  src={&apos;/static/images/blog/sometimes-humans-just-need-to-sit-in-one-place-and-like-hurt/sit-and-hurt.gif&apos;}
  width={1905 / 2}
  height={957 / 2}
  layout=&quot;responsive&quot;
  blurDataURL={
    &apos;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAQAAAACCAIAAADwyuo0AAAACXBIWXMAAA7EAAAOxAGVKw4bAAAAIklEQVQImWNgYBDnFZCxsfc0tvJkCI/O+vP/f0tdhZK8CgBLPAfARKUieAAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==&apos;
  }
  placeholder=&quot;blur&quot;
/&gt;

After writing about being in a creative slump, a few kind strangers generously offered helpful suggestions: schedule a time to write each day, keep a journal (private is fine), stay consistent. I&apos;ll do my best to implement all of them, and even if I don&apos;t succeed, it&apos;s comforting to know I&apos;m not alone in this. Thanks to everyone who wrote to me with suggestions! I truly appreciate them all.

I stumbled across Julia Cameron&apos;s Morning Pages journaling exercise, and it strikes me as the perfect way to maintain a journaling habit. I like not having a set prompt or restrictions that tell me what to or not to write. The hardest part for me now (other than actually sitting down and journaling) is finding paper that will tolerate my fountain pens without breaking the bank. I&apos;ll probably end up flouting the &apos;longhand&apos; part of Julia&apos;s exercise and doing it in a text editor like I am now.

Writing at a set time each day has proven difficult for me to stick with. I made plans to call a friend abroad this Monday morning, and the call lasted almost three hours. I didn&apos;t mean to blow through my morning writing window, but the conversation was engaging and gave me plenty to chew on, so I&apos;d say it was a net positive for my writing, even if it hampered my schedule.

The last time I talked to this particular friend was more than a year ago, so we spent most of our time catching up on major life events. I was surprised to learn that she&apos;d also been cheated on by her (now former, thankfully) partner earlier this year (around when the same happened to me). As my heart ached with sympathy, I felt an odd sort of kinship arise within me for her. Being cheated on is a strange experience because there&apos;s no amount of explanation that can convey what it feels like to someone who hasn&apos;t been there, yet there&apos;s not that much to say to people who have been there either. They already know what it feels like through their own experience anyway, and no words can do that sort of pain justice. It was incredibly validating to hear us both come to the same lessons from our months of recovery: of growth, forgiveness, and empathy.

One of the significant lessons we&apos;ve both learned in our recovery process is that forgiveness is about recognizing that other people&apos;s actions aren&apos;t a reflection of who we are but who they are. Most people who cheat don&apos;t set out to do something so terrible or hurtful (the road to hell is paved with good intentions, after all) but are just trying their best to cope with their fears, insecurities, and trauma. I don&apos;t mean this to absolve them of their wrongdoing, but I had to accept this before I could understand and, through that understanding, let go of my anger. You can start to feel sympathy for people in this way, even if they&apos;ve done terrible things to you. As my friend quoted, &quot;hurt people hurt people.&quot; And that realization can be liberating, even if it doesn&apos;t make the bitterness, pain, or anger dissipate immediately.

There&apos;s a DFW quote that goes something like, sometimes human beings have to just sit in one place and, like, hurt, and my mind wanders to it whenever I think about what I went through this year. When I suffered from excruciating pain, I desperately wanted something to take it away: a friend, a therapist, a new city, at times even the very person who caused the pain in the first place. But there&apos;s nothing that will really make you feel better. Nobody can bear the pain for you; you just have to sit with it until it subsides. And it might take a long time, but it will get better eventually.

I&apos;m grateful for the wisdom pain has taught me this year, but I still miss the sort of youthful innocence I used to have (and still see in my friends who haven&apos;t suffered the same fate). I&apos;ll miss trusting by default, rather than needing to consciously decide to place my trust in someone, and I have a feeling I&apos;m going to always have to choose to ignore certain hurtful voices in my head which were silent before but are now empowered by betrayal.

We also chatted about the challenges of making new friends as an adult, especially in a foreign country/culture. I struggled with this when I was abroad and continue to struggle with it now, and we both commiserated over how rare it is to find someone that really clicks, &quot;vibes,&quot; or is &quot;on the same wavelength&quot; with us, however you put it. In my experience, it rarely has anything to do with shared interests (which is how people typically try to look for friends), and I can&apos;t judge whether I&apos;ll click with someone until I talk to them and spend time with them in person. I&apos;ve tried for years to dissect the components of this compatibility, or what makes my conversations with some people light up where others sputter out, but it&apos;s incredibly difficult for me to distill any useful insights. (I&apos;m not an impartial observer, and observing things can cause them to act differently, kind of like a variation of the Heisenberg uncertainty principle?)

I will say one of the (perhaps not so profound) observations I&apos;ve made about my friends I love talking to is that they not only listen and understand what I tell them without too much effort, but also that they convey to me that they understand, ideally with their own subtle thought-provoking twist or spin. I do believe there are a good portion of people in this world who understand me but who can&apos;t consistently demonstrate that they do (heck, I&apos;ve met plenty of them myself), and in my experience conveying to me that you understand is almost as important (or just as much) as understanding me in the first place. (I also believe there are people who are the inverse of this, who can make me believe they understand me when they actually don&apos;t. I try to stay away from these people.)

(Enjoy this Venn diagram I made of this, not drawn to scale. I really like when people draw up cute little graphics to illustrate concepts.)
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/blog/sometimes-humans-just-need-to-sit-in-one-place-and-like-hurt/graphic.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Venn diagram of understanding and conveying understanding&quot; /&gt;

Yours, Yuri Cunha.

I submitted my formal application to coach kids writing this morning after the recruiter got back to me. I felt a bit embarrassed submitting an analytical writing sample that I&apos;d written when I was thirteen and a creative writing sample from not much later (gosh—my Rupi Kaur phase is not something I want to relive), and I&apos;m still cringing about it hours later. But, like someone who wrote me yesterday said, this feeling is fine (even normal), and the &quot;key is to not let it stop you from doing something entirely.&quot; There&apos;s no point in me deciding if my writing is good or not anyway. I&apos;m better off letting them decide for themselves, and if they like my writing and decide to accept me, great! If they don&apos;t, well, I still have my precious free time.</content:encoded>
            <author>
                <name>yuricunha</name>
                <email>hidden</email>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why I Abandoned Social Media]]></title>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">Why I Abandoned Social Media</guid>
            <id>https://localhost:3000/blogs/why-i-abandoned-social-media</id>
            <updated>2023-10-31T14:40:00-03:00</updated>
            <description>Exploring the reasons behind my decision to leave the world of social media and embrace a more private and independent digital life.</description>
            <image>/static/images/blog/why-i-abandoned-social-media/why-i-abandoned-social-media.png</image>
            <content:encoded>
&lt;Image
  alt={
    &quot;Exploring the reasons behind my decision to leave the world of social media and embrace a more private and independent digital life.&quot;
  }
  src={&apos;/static/images/blog/why-i-abandoned-social-media/why-i-abandoned-social-media.png&apos;}
  width={1905 / 2}
  height={957 / 2}
  layout=&quot;responsive&quot;
  blurDataURL={
    &apos;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAQAAAACCAIAAADwyuo0AAAACXBIWXMAAA7EAAAOxAGVKw4bAAAAIklEQVQImWNgYBDnFZCxsfc0tvJkCI/O+vP/f0tdhZK8CgBLPAfARKUieAAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==&apos;
  }
  placeholder=&quot;blur&quot;
/&gt;

It has been five years since I started my first blog, or even 15/16 years if you count my Tumblr as a blog. It&apos;s almost incredible, isn&apos;t it?

Over the course of several years, I&apos;ve witnessed social media platforms come and go. Some have thrived for years, while others lost their appeal. However, the truth is that most of them are still here today, with the less famous ones being less frequently used. But I&apos;m not here to determine which ones have more or less merit or to say which social network is better or worse.

I considered a more sensationalistic, yet realistic, title for this post: &quot;Why Social Media Died for Me.&quot; However, I decided against using that title as it didn&apos;t quite resonate with me.

Since my late teens, I&apos;ve been gradually distancing myself from social media. Surprisingly, I was once &quot;famous&quot; on platforms like Twitter, Instagram, and Facebook, boasting around 100,000 followers on each and 1,000 to 5,000 likes on a simple &quot;hello.&quot; But those periods of fame were short-lived for me because I would simply give away, sell, delete, or change my username, abandoning social networks at random. Why did I do this? It all came down to one thing: saturation.

Even though I still receive numerous messages and notifications in my DMs today, I don&apos;t read them. I don&apos;t read them because I don&apos;t use social media anymore, and I simply don&apos;t enjoy it. If you&apos;ve ever watched the TV series &quot;Mr. Robot,&quot; in which Rami Malek portrays Elliot Alderson (you should watch it), he says in the first episode of the first season (Episode 1 - Season 1), &quot;Oh, I don&apos;t know, is it that we collectively thought Steve Jobs was a great man even when we knew he made billions off the backs of children? Or maybe it&apos;s that it feels like all our heroes are counterfeit; the world itself&apos;s just one big hoax. Spamming each other with our burning commentary of bulls**t masquerading as insight, our social media faking as intimacy. Or is it that we voted for this? Not with our rigged elections, but with our things, our property, our money. I&apos;m not saying anything new. We all know why we do this, not because Hunger Games books make us happy but because we wanna be sedated. Because it&apos;s painful not to pretend, because we&apos;re cowards.&quot; If you pause to analyze it for a moment, it aligns with what was said in the ninth episode of the first season (Episode 9 - Season 1): &quot;Is any of it real? I mean, look at this. Look at it! A world built on fantasy! Synthetic emotions in the form of pills, psychological warfare in the form of advertising, mind-altering chemicals in the form of food, brainwashing seminars in the form of media, controlled isolated bubbles in the form of social networks.&quot; You don&apos;t need to be a genius to understand the basics: people spend their entire days on social media, pretending to be close to the people they interact with.

Social media platforms are increasingly eroding your privacy, sharing and disseminating everything you do, from the name of your device to your IP-based location. Most people accept this without even realizing what&apos;s happening because they don&apos;t read privacy policies or the cookies that are tracking them. Consequently, our screens are inundated with targeted advertisements collected through insane telemetry. But that&apos;s not even the worst part.

Perhaps the most significant issue is that everything has become artificial, and there&apos;s no desire to have real, in-person interactions anymore. Nowadays, if someone wants to see you, they video call you. I can understand this if you live far away, but if you&apos;re within a 15-30-minute drive, go and meet the person in real life. Companies in Brazil send messages via a messaging app called WhatsApp instead of calling, sending SMS/MMS, or emailing. This raises questions about the depth of these interactions and the invasion of privacy. If you didn&apos;t explicitly provide your WhatsApp number or agree to communicate through it, who said you could be contacted using it? I once had WhatsApp, but I no longer do, and I don&apos;t intend to have it. I use Telegram and Session, but even then, I only talk to a few people (around 15-20), and Telegram is sparsely used in Brazil.

The craziest part of it all is that here, if you don&apos;t have WhatsApp, you&apos;re considered a &quot;fake&quot; person (someone who is pretending or not genuine). The need for people to prove themselves is so great that they might stop talking to you if you don&apos;t have WhatsApp or Instagram, even if you have SMS/MMS/Telegram/Session/calling/iMessage/Samsung Message.

In the end, one of the primary reasons I abandoned social media and &quot;private&quot; messaging platforms (I&apos;ve never seen true E2E encryption, as claimed by Meta&apos;s WhatsApp, which can access your conversations) is the lack of security and privacy. For instance, in cases where the government or individuals request conversations, the app may provide them, despite claiming that the conversations are end-to-end encrypted, as in the case of Meta&apos;s services (WhatsApp, Instagram, and Facebook). On the other hand, I stick with Session and Telegram because on numerous occasions, governments and individuals have requested chat logs that both parties don&apos;t have and can&apos;t provide since they don&apos;t have access to them.

The bottom line is that nowadays, people are pretending to be close while industries are getting richer by selling you. After all, by basic logic, if you&apos;re not paying for the product, you are the product. Aside from the dissemination of utterly meaningless content with no real substance or value that many people consume, I fail to see the reason behind it. We are part of a generation with easier and quicker access to articles, materials, and education, yet we manage to be one of the least intelligent generations to date.

This time, I&apos;ll conclude here. If you ever intend to get in touch with me, you can find me via email ([isyuricunha@duck.com](mailto:isyuricunha@duck.com)). I hope you enjoyed this post, and I&apos;ll see you next time. Bye! 👋</content:encoded>
            <author>
                <name>yuricunha</name>
                <email>hidden</email>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Unconventional Bonds of Friendship and Solitude]]></title>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">The Unconventional Bonds of Friendship and Solitude</guid>
            <id>https://localhost:3000/blogs/the-unconventional-bonds-of-friendship-and-solitude</id>
            <updated>2023-10-18T06:10:57-03:00</updated>
            <description>My friends. My mind. Myself.</description>
            <image>/static/images/blog/the-unconventional-bonds-of-friendship-and-solitude/loneliness-crowd.jpg</image>
            <content:encoded>
&lt;Image
  alt={&apos;Around world alone, but not alone.&apos;}
  src={
    &apos;/static/images/blog/the-unconventional-bonds-of-friendship-and-solitude/loneliness-crowd.jpg&apos;
  }
  width={1905 / 2}
  height={957 / 2}
  layout=&quot;responsive&quot;
  blurDataURL={
    &apos;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAQAAAACCAIAAADwyuo0AAAACXBIWXMAAA7EAAAOxAGVKw4bAAAAIklEQVQImWNgYBDnFZCxsfc0tvJkCI/O+vP/f0tdhZK8CgBLPAfARKUieAAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==&apos;
  }
  placeholder=&quot;blur&quot;
/&gt;

I&apos;m not exactly sure where or how to start this article, or even if I should call it an article, despite being a blog post...

In the early hours of the morning today, I went out to smoke a cigarette, and as always, I found myself pondering about the things in my world. I call it my world because I don&apos;t tend to encompass everything that happens in my life. If something isn&apos;t directly related to me or doesn&apos;t interfere with my life, I usually ignore it.

While I was smoking, I was thinking that, despite having few friends (three, to be precise – I didn&apos;t even need to count), I am fortunate to have them.

Since the beginning of 2022, it has become increasingly challenging to want to be alive or to want to do anything. Perhaps it&apos;s because I failed in some areas of my life where I aimed for success, or simply because I didn&apos;t achieve what I wanted. But it&apos;s not that I&apos;ve given up because in everything I failed at or didn&apos;t do, I intend to try again or start over. After all, I already know where or how I went wrong; I just need to fix it or begin anew and do better/differently. The craziest part of all this is that every time something doesn&apos;t go well or doesn&apos;t work out, these three friends of mine have always been there.

I&apos;m not a person who spends a lot of time with family or the like, partly because I barely talk to them or see them. I also don&apos;t particularly enjoy family gatherings or celebratory occasions like birthdays and the like. And being an atheist, I don&apos;t celebrate religious holidays either. Being an atheist, it seems that people see me as a bad guy, morally deficient, or completely wrong – it&apos;s quite amusing, actually.

Even after saying all this, there are things that just seem like madness, you know, like most people praising me too much, saying I&apos;m very intelligent, knowledgeable in various subjects, and able to explain many things. But this isn&apos;t about intelligence; it&apos;s because I&apos;ve taken so many courses (I&apos;ve passed 100 – congratulations to me), read so many books (I don&apos;t like ebooks), and seen so much that I simply learn/learned from it. It&apos;s amazing, you know? It&apos;s crazy to go to a place or even some social gathering (even if I don&apos;t enjoy it) and see people&apos;s eyes light up when they discuss a subject, and I start delving into the details, mentioning references and even showing where those references can be found. It&apos;s simply rewarding. But the flip side of the coin also reveals itself because when the conversation ends or the person leaves, the lightness turns into heaviness or exhaustion, and my social battery is drained. Can you understand how insane that sounds?

Now, switching topics a bit, one of the three friends I mentioned, in this case, Lucas, whom I&apos;ve known for 11/12 years (a considerable amount of time), is someone I can have endless conversations with. We practically talk every day throughout all this time, and the craziest part is that Lucas is just like me. We don&apos;t keep saying that we like each other, but we share various similar ideas, even if we have different views on the same subject. This guy has been by my side in some pretty grim moments of my life, maybe even some dark times.

As for another of my three friends, Vinicius (who is also my cousin), we don&apos;t talk every day, but this guy saved me from certain suicide, which was one of the darkest periods in my life. I even spent some time at his place. I needed to be alone, quiet, and, at most, have a conversation with someone. Of course, while I was there, I also went out with friends for drinks and outings, but the coolest part of it all was coming back and seeing one of my three brothers there, with me.

And now there&apos;s the newest addition to my count of three friends, Vitor... an amazing guy with crazy ideas (reminds me of myself), another person who saved me from various situations and saved me from myself. We&apos;ve spent hours on Discord, sometimes falling asleep in a call, just chatting or discussing something completely random. Hahahahahah.

I don&apos;t need the world&apos;s approval, and I&apos;m not afraid to speak honestly and directly to people. But with these guys, I&apos;m a bit cautious. I don&apos;t know if it&apos;s because I&apos;m afraid of losing them in my life or if it&apos;s a fear of not having them around anymore. I don&apos;t know, but it&apos;s impossible for me to look to the side and imagine my life without these crazy people. I have few friends, but they are quality friends.

Transitioning from one extreme to the other, whenever I stop to think (well, I think while being still, hehe), I reflect on how my blood family, who share my DNA, knows so little about me. I&apos;ve done and am doing so many things that only one of my three best friends knows or that only I know. I could say, &quot;I don&apos;t know the reason for this,&quot; but I do know: I don&apos;t want to share it with them. It&apos;s not that I don&apos;t want to share my life with my family, but I can&apos;t see myself doing it. I like being alone, being by myself. It&apos;s one of the reasons why I spend almost 24/7 with my headphones on and mostly on my computer. I read, study, take my courses, earn my money, talk to my best friends, and then I can just be quiet. Most people seem to want someone around or feel that if they&apos;re away from their family, they&apos;ll go crazy or just not feel right. But it doesn&apos;t work that way for me. If people don&apos;t talk to me, that&apos;s fine. If they do, that&apos;s fine too. As I mentioned before, I don&apos;t need approval or recognition. I like being this way.

I have ideas and thoughts that, because they&apos;re not popular nowadays, most people think I&apos;m radical. But they seem not to understand the difference between radical and what I want, just as they confuse indifference with apathy.

I remember when my mom (actually my grandmother, but I call her mom) passed away, and people started wondering who would attend the funeral, who would speak or not, who didn&apos;t attend didn&apos;t care, and so on. But I think differently because each person has their way of dealing with grief. Some take time to understand, some don&apos;t want to accept, and some accept and move on, as in my case. But what people don&apos;t understand is that we all feel the same, but because we&apos;re more steadfast, we might end up crying alone, not in public. We are distant, and we like to be alone in these moments. When we see someone sad or crying, we hug the person or stay quiet because that&apos;s how we like it, and we tend to think that people like it that way too, even though we know that the person usually likes company. In that moment, we stay away because they might not want it at that time, so we keep to ourselves.

Maybe the general societal mistake or the popular thoughts is assuming that we don&apos;t have feelings or don&apos;t think about things, but we do. Some show it less, some show it more, and we have thoughts, usually more rational and logical than those who are openly suffering. But our difference is that our minds aren&apos;t clouded and confused, or if they are, we&apos;re thinking about how to organize and do things based on logic and reason, not feelings and emotion.

Well, that&apos;s it.
</content:encoded>
            <author>
                <name>yuricunha</name>
                <email>hidden</email>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I Don't Care]]></title>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">I Don&apos;t Care</guid>
            <id>https://localhost:3000/blogs/i-dont-care</id>
            <updated>2023-10-11T15:58:57-03:00</updated>
            <description>I&apos;m not a mean person. I don&apos;t go out of my way to hurt people&apos;s feelings. But I also don&apos;t care about most people or most things that don&apos;t involve me.</description>
            <image>/static/images/blog/i-dont-care/idontcare.jpg</image>
            <content:encoded>
&lt;Image
  alt={
    &quot;I&apos;m not a mean person. I don&apos;t go out of my way to hurt people&apos;s feelings. But I also don&apos;t care about most people or most things that don&apos;t involve me.&quot;
  }
  src={&apos;/static/images/blog/i-dont-care/idontcare.jpg&apos;}
  width={1905 / 2}
  height={957 / 2}
  layout=&quot;responsive&quot;
  blurDataURL={
    &apos;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAQAAAACCAIAAADwyuo0AAAACXBIWXMAAA7EAAAOxAGVKw4bAAAAIklEQVQImWNgYBDnFZCxsfc0tvJkCI/O+vP/f0tdhZK8CgBLPAfARKUieAAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==&apos;
  }
  placeholder=&quot;blur&quot;
/&gt;

I&apos;ve always been like this. I was a shy kid with few friends. I preferred spending time alone, reading books, or playing video games.

As I got older, I realized I don&apos;t need to care about what others think. I don&apos;t have to pretend to be interested in things I&apos;m not. I can just be myself.

I&apos;m not saying I&apos;m completely indifferent to everyone. I have a few close friends and family members I deeply care about. But for the most part, I just don&apos;t care.

I don&apos;t care about what people wear or what they do with their lives. I don&apos;t care about the latest news or gossip. I don&apos;t care about what&apos;s going on in the world.

Some people find my indifference off-putting, thinking I&apos;m rude or arrogant. But I&apos;m not. I&apos;m just being honest.

I won&apos;t pretend to care about something I don&apos;t. I won&apos;t waste my time and energy on things that don&apos;t matter to me.

**Benefits of Indifference**

Indifference has freed me from the expectations of others. I don&apos;t have to worry about what they think or want me to be. I can just be myself.

It lets me focus on what&apos;s important to me. I don&apos;t waste time and energy on what doesn&apos;t matter. I focus on my passions and my relationships with people I care about.

It&apos;s made me more resilient. I&apos;m not easily bothered by setbacks or disappointments. I know life has ups and downs, and I don&apos;t let the downs get me down.

**Choices**

I sat in the park, and Sarah approached me with a weary look, like a shipwrecked sailor seeking salvation. She unleashed a torrent of complaints about her life – her toxic relationship, her soul-sucking job, and her endlessly problematic family.

She rambled on, spilling her guts, hoping for some kind words, a pat on the back, or a sprinkle of sympathy. But as she finally took a breath, I couldn&apos;t sugarcoat the apathy that coursed through my veins.

&quot;Sarah,&quot; I said bluntly, &quot;you&apos;ve been moaning about this for ages. Frankly, I&apos;m tired of hearing the same sob story. If you&apos;re so miserable, why don&apos;t you just do something about it? I can&apos;t be bothered with your drama.&quot;

Her eyes widened in disbelief, and her hopes shattered like glass. She had expected compassion, but what she got was a harsh dose of reality.

&quot;Yuri,&quot; she stammered, &quot;I thought you&apos;d at least pretend to care. You&apos;re so heartless.&quot;

I shrugged indifferently. &quot;Pretending is not my style, Sarah. You&apos;re stuck in a self-imposed mess, and my patience is wearing thin. You&apos;re the one who needs to decide whether you want to keep wallowing in self-pity or actually do something.&quot;

Sarah left, crushed and flabbergasted, and I was left to my own thoughts. Sometimes, the truth is bitter medicine, and not everyone can swallow it without choking. But in a world where I didn&apos;t care about most things, I couldn&apos;t afford to sugarcoat reality, even if it meant sacrificing a friendship.

After Sarah stormed off, I remained seated, unfazed by her exit. I&apos;d done what I believed was right. Indifference had its virtues, but it also had its harsh edges.

A week later, Sarah contacted me again. She had taken some time to digest our conversation, and perhaps a hint of realization had seeped in. She seemed more composed this time, her expectations seemingly adjusted.

&quot;Yuri,&quot; she began cautiously, &quot;I&apos;ve thought about what you said, and it stung. But I can&apos;t help but admit that you might be onto something. Maybe I&apos;ve been stuck in this rut for too long.&quot;

I didn&apos;t mince words. &quot;Sarah, I had to be brutally honest because you were stuck in a never-ending cycle of complaints without taking action. If you&apos;re finally realizing that, then it&apos;s a step in the right direction.&quot;

She nodded, acknowledging my point. &quot;I can&apos;t blame you for being straightforward. I guess it&apos;s time for me to make some changes, for real this time.&quot;

I gave her a curt nod. &quot;Good. Remember, I don&apos;t care about your complaints, but I do care about you. If you&apos;re ready to change, I&apos;m here to support you.&quot;

Sarah&apos;s face displayed a mix of determination and resignation. She had learned the hard way that complaining wasn&apos;t going to change her circumstances. It was up to her to make a choice: remain in the same rut or take action to create a better life. My indifference had served as a stark reminder that, sometimes, the most valuable advice is the one we don&apos;t want to hear.

Shortly after my candid conversation with Sarah, another incident occurred that highlighted my unique perspective on empathy. It was my cousin, Alex, who approached me this time. I could tell he was trying to choose his words carefully, and I braced myself for what was to come.

&quot;Yuri,&quot; Alex began, &quot;I know we&apos;re family, but I need to tell you something. Our distant relative, Aunt Margot, passed away.&quot;

I stared at him blankly, my indifference apparent. Aunt Margot was someone I&apos;d never met, had no connection with, and certainly didn&apos;t care about. She was just a distant figure in the family tree, someone I had no reason to mourn.

Alex mustered a weak smile, as if trying to appeal to some hidden well of empathy within me. &quot;I thought you should know because, well, we are related.&quot;

I shook my head, unapologetically blunt. &quot;Alex, I appreciate you letting me know, but I have no emotional connection to Aunt Margot. We may share some distant bloodline, but that doesn&apos;t mean I&apos;m going to pretend to grieve for someone I never knew.&quot;

Alex&apos;s smile faded, replaced by an awkward silence. He had probably expected some form of sympathy, even from a distant relative, but he was met with my cold and unapologetic indifference.

I could sense the unease in the air as Alex realized that I wasn&apos;t going to play the part of the grieving family member. In a world where I didn&apos;t care about most things or most people, I couldn&apos;t fake emotions or empathy for someone I had no connection to.

**Dealing with People Who Don&apos;t Understand**

Some people find my indifference off-putting, thinking I&apos;m rude or arrogant. But I&apos;m not. I&apos;m just being honest.

I try to be patient and understanding with those who don&apos;t get it. I explain I care about them but not most things. I respect their opinions, even if I disagree.

If someone&apos;s rude or disrespectful because of my indifference, I walk away. I don&apos;t have time for negative, judgmental people.

**How to Be Indifferent**

If you want to be more indifferent, here are some tips:

- **Identify what you care about.** Focus on what&apos;s truly important to you, and let go of the rest.
- **Don&apos;t compare yourself to others.** Everyone is different, with unique goals and values.
- **Accept that you can&apos;t control everything.** Focus on what&apos;s within your control.
- **Let go of expectations.** Expectations lead to disappointment.
- **Practice mindfulness.** Stay in the present without judgment.

Additional tips:

- **Don&apos;t take things personally.** Most people aren&apos;t trying to hurt you.
- **Don&apos;t dwell on the past.** It&apos;s over, and you can&apos;t change it.
- **Don&apos;t worry about the future.** Focus on the present and live in the now.

Remember, indifference doesn&apos;t mean apathy. You can be indifferent to some things and passionate about others. It&apos;s challenging but worthwhile in the long run, leading to a more peaceful and fulfilling life.

**Advice to Others**

If you struggle with indifference:

- It&apos;s okay not to care about everything.
- Focus on what matters to you.
- Don&apos;t let others&apos; opinions bother you.
- Be yourself, not who others want you to be.
- Don&apos;t waste time and energy on what doesn&apos;t matter.

![Image of a person sitting alone in a park](https://yuricunha.com/static/images/blog/i-dont-care/lonely-in-park.jpg)
</content:encoded>
            <author>
                <name>yuricunha</name>
                <email>hidden</email>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Confessing my Stupidity]]></title>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">Confessing my Stupidity</guid>
            <id>https://localhost:3000/blogs/confessing-my-stupidity</id>
            <updated>2023-08-26T00:00:00.751-03:00</updated>
            <description>A candid reflection on my lack of intelligence and how I&apos;m dealing with it.</description>
            <image>/static/images/blog/confessing-my-stupidity/confessing-my-stupidity.jpg</image>
            <content:encoded>
&lt;Image
  alt={
    &quot;A candid reflection on my lack of intelligence and how I&apos;m dealing with it.&quot;
  }
  src={
    &apos;/static/images/blog/confessing-my-stupidity/confessing-my-stupidity.jpg&apos;
  }
  width={1905 / 2}
  height={957 / 2}
  layout=&quot;responsive&quot;
  blurDataURL={
    &apos;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAQAAAACCAIAAADwyuo0AAAACXBIWXMAAA7EAAAOxAGVKw4bAAAAIklEQVQImWNgYBDnFZCxsfc0tvJkCI/O+vP/f0tdhZK8CgBLPAfARKUieAAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==&apos;
  }
  placeholder=&quot;blur&quot;
/&gt;

# Confessing my Stupidity

Alright, time to spill the beans. This confession has been building up for a while, and now that I&apos;m a full-fledged adult juggling a job and bills, there&apos;s no avoiding it.

So here it goes: I&apos;m not exactly a genius.

It all started with a friend who admitted to putting off embracing her true self, and it got me thinking. This feeling has been lurking around since I was a kid. Everyone around me was hitting the books, and hey, I lucked out too and got to do the same. But there&apos;s been this gap that&apos;s become more pronounced as we&apos;ve all grown up.

I&apos;m surrounded by these amazing folks—smart, insightful individuals. People who&apos;ve got something to say. People who&apos;ve dived into books and come up with specialized knowledge. Folks who understand their crafts and can put things together. People who aren&apos;t just capable of skimming the surface but can really get a grip on a situation or topic. And then they take the time to break it down for me. I love it when my pals chat about world events and make connections. Their excitement is infectious, and I relish listening to them. I appreciate those who write or make videos about what they know, so I can unabashedly try to pick up a thing or two.

But now, let&apos;s come clean: my noggin is seriously lacking. There&apos;s no groundbreaking or original thoughts™ happening up there.

Wanna hear something funny? I&apos;ve got a subscription to a money-focused and politics-focused newspaper, all in an attempt to get a better grip on reality like my buddies. I wanted to join the conversation, add something to it. Can you guess what happened? I&apos;m clueless when it comes to stuff like inflation, stocks, or geopolitics. But don&apos;t get me wrong, I won&apos;t stop reading. I&apos;m a reading enthusiast, after all.

My brain kind of throws in the towel when it comes to understanding. I can read, but it&apos;s like the knowledge doesn&apos;t quite stick; I can listen, but the bigger picture doesn&apos;t click. Opinions? Nope. Conclusions? Not my strong suit. Head? Basically empty.

Happy elevator music plays in the background as my brain takes its owner (aka &quot;meatbag&quot;) out for a spin. I&apos;m embracing my inner fool and waving goodbye to pretending. No more trying to sound like a smarty-pants. No more stressing about needing to be more than I am. Because honestly, it&apos;s more crucial to know what I can handle rather than clumsily fighting against myself. It&apos;s not that I&apos;m giving up on understanding; it&apos;s more like I&apos;m acknowledging my boundaries. I&apos;m done with the self-inflicted headache over my thought process (or lack thereof, most of the time).

I&apos;m not a brainiac, and who knows, I might never be. And that&apos;s perfectly fine. Life&apos;s a blast, filled with things waiting to be explored. I enjoy watching bumblebees do their thing around flowers, and I get a kick out of observing everyone living their lives. If I&apos;m the everyday dunce, at least I&apos;m aiming to be a kind one.

&lt;Aside type={&apos;positive&apos;} title={&apos;Thank you very much for reading!&apos;}&gt;
  Whilst I do write these for myself, it&apos;s also great if it helps other people
  out! So thank you for reading through and I hope I helped you out just a
  little bit. Become a
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sponsors/isyuricunha&quot;&gt; sponsor&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/Aside&gt;
</content:encoded>
            <author>
                <name>yuricunha</name>
                <email>hidden</email>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[dAppling Network: A Simple Solution for Hosting Censorship-Resistant Web3 Frontends]]></title>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">dAppling Network: A Simple Solution for Hosting Censorship-Resistant Web3 Frontends</guid>
            <id>https://localhost:3000/blogs/dAppling</id>
            <updated>2023-07-29T14:25:27.751-03:00</updated>
            <description>dAppling Network is a new web hosting service that is built specifically for Web3 protocols. It uses the InterPlanetary File System (IPFS) to store and serve frontend code, which makes it censorship-resistant and decentralized. dAppling also provides a number of other features that make it a valuable tool for Web3 developers, including verifiable deployments, smart contract-controlled frontends, and performance.</description>
            <image>/static/images/blog/dappling-network/dappling.jpg</image>
            <content:encoded>
&lt;Image
  alt={
    &apos;dAppling Network is a new web hosting service that is built specifically for Web3 protocols. It uses the InterPlanetary File System (IPFS) to store and serve frontend code, which makes it censorship-resistant and decentralized. dAppling also provides a number of other features that make it a valuable tool for Web3 developers, including verifiable deployments, smart contract-controlled frontends, and performance. - Image by dAppling Network twitter.&apos;
  }
  src={&apos;/static/images/blog/dappling-network/dappling.jpg&apos;}
  width={1905 / 2}
  height={957 / 2}
  layout=&quot;responsive&quot;
  blurDataURL={
    &apos;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAQAAAACCAIAAADwyuo0AAAACXBIWXMAAA7EAAAOxAGVKw4bAAAAIklEQVQImWNgYBDnFZCxsfc0tvJkCI/O+vP/f0tdhZK8CgBLPAfARKUieAAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==&apos;
  }
  placeholder=&quot;blur&quot;
/&gt;

# Introduction

The decentralized web is growing rapidly, but one of the biggest challenges facing developers is finding a way to host their frontends in a way that is censorship-resistant and secure. dAppling Network is a new platform that aims to solve this problem by providing a simple and easy-to-use way to host decentralized frontends.

# What is dAppling Network?

dAppling Network is a web hosting service built specifically for Web3 protocols. It uses the InterPlanetary File System (IPFS) to store and serve frontend code, which makes it censorship-resistant and decentralized. dAppling also provides a number of other features that make it a valuable tool for Web3 developers, including:

- **Verifiable deployments:** dAppling uses a verifiable deployment process that ensures that your frontend code is deployed correctly and that it cannot be tampered with.
- **Smart contract-controlled frontends:** dAppling allows you to control your frontends using smart contracts, which gives you even more control over your applications.
- **Performance:** dAppling uses IPFS to serve your frontend code, which makes it very performant.

# How does dAppling work?

To use dAppling, you simply need to create an account and upload your frontend code. dAppling will then deploy your code to IPFS and generate a URL that you can use to access your frontend.

# Why use dAppling Network?

There are a number of reasons why you should use dAppling Network to host your frontends, including:

- **Censorship resistance:** dAppling is censorship-resistant because it uses IPFS to store and serve your frontend code. This means that your frontend cannot be censored by governments or other organizations.
- **Security:** dAppling uses a number of security features to protect your frontends, including verifiable deployments and smart contract-controlled frontends.
- **Performance:** dAppling uses IPFS to serve your frontend code, which makes it very performant.
- **Ease of use:** dAppling is very easy to use. You can create an account and deploy your frontend in just a few minutes.

# dAppling Network is constantly updating

dAppling Network is a rapidly evolving platform, and the team is constantly working to improve the platform. Some of the areas that dAppling is constantly updating include:

- **Security:** dAppling is committed to providing the highest level of security for its users. The team is constantly working to improve the security of the platform, including implementing new security features and hardening the existing security measures.

- **Performance:** dAppling is also committed to providing the best possible performance for its users. The team is constantly working to optimize the platform for performance, including improving the caching mechanisms and optimizing the code.

- **Features:** dAppling is also constantly adding new features to the platform. The team is listening to the feedback from users and adding features that are requested by the community.

# Conclusion

dAppling Network is a powerful new platform that makes it easy to host censorship-resistant and secure frontends for your Web3 applications. If you are a Web3 developer, I encourage you to check out dAppling Network.

# Call to action

To learn more about dAppling Network, visit their website at [www.dappling.network](https://www.dappling.network/landing). You can also follow them on Twitter at [@dApplingNetwork](https://twitter.com/dApplingNetwork).

# FAQs

**Q: What are the benefits of using dAppling Network over other web hosting services?**

A: dAppling Network offers a number of benefits over other web hosting services, including:

- **Censorship resistance:** dAppling is censorship-resistant because it uses IPFS to store and serve your frontend code. This means that your frontend cannot be censored by governments or other organizations.
- **Security:** dAppling uses a number of security features to protect your frontends, including verifiable deployments and smart contract-controlled frontends.
- **Performance:** dAppling uses IPFS to serve your frontend code, which makes it very performant.
- **Ease of use:** dAppling is very easy to use. You can create an account and deploy your frontend in just a few minutes.

**Q: What are the limitations of dAppling Network?**

A: dAppling Network is still under development, so there are a few limitations to the platform. For example, dAppling does not currently support all of the features that are available on traditional web hosting services. However, the dAppling team is constantly working to improve the platform, so these limitations are likely to be addressed in the future.

**Q: What are the costs of using dAppling Network?**

A: dAppling Network is free to use for basic accounts. However, there are some premium features that require a paid subscription. The cost of a premium subscription depends on the number of frontends that you want to host.

**Q: How do I get started with dAppling Network?**

A: To get started with dAppling Network, you simply need to create an account and upload your frontend code. dAppling will then deploy your code to IPFS and generate a URL that you can use to access your frontend.

**Q: What are the technical requirements for using dAppling Network?**

A: The only technical requirement for using dAppling Network is that you have a web browser. dAppling can be used to host frontends for any Web3 protocol.

&lt;Aside type={&apos;positive&apos;} title={&apos;Thank you very much for reading!&apos;}&gt;
  Whilst I do write these for myself, it&apos;s also great if it helps other people
  out! So thank you for reading through and I hope I helped you out just a
  little bit. Become a
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sponsors/isyuricunha&quot;&gt; sponsor&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/Aside&gt;
</content:encoded>
            <author>
                <name>yuricunha</name>
                <email>hidden</email>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Privacy Has Become Increasingly Important.]]></title>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">How Privacy Has Become Increasingly Important.</guid>
            <id>https://localhost:3000/blogs/how-privacy-has-become-increasingly-important</id>
            <updated>2023-07-05T08:55:27.751-03:00</updated>
            <description>An exploration of the increasing significance of privacy in today&apos;s digital world, emphasizing the need to safeguard personal information and protect autonomy.</description>
            <image>/static/images/blog/how-privacy-has-become-increasingly-important/privacy.png</image>
            <content:encoded>
&lt;Image
  alt={
    &quot;An exploration of the increasing significance of privacy in today&apos;s digital world, emphasizing the need to safeguard personal information and protect autonomy.&quot;
  }
  src={
    &apos;/static/images/blog/how-privacy-has-become-increasingly-important/privacy.png&apos;
  }
  width={1905 / 2}
  height={957 / 2}
  layout=&quot;responsive&quot;
  blurDataURL={
    &apos;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAQAAAACCAIAAADwyuo0AAAACXBIWXMAAA7EAAAOxAGVKw4bAAAAIklEQVQImWNgYBDnFZCxsfc0tvJkCI/O+vP/f0tdhZK8CgBLPAfARKUieAAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==&apos;
  }
  placeholder=&quot;blur&quot;
/&gt;

# How Privacy Has Become Increasingly Important

## Introduction

In the digital age, privacy has emerged as a paramount concern for individuals and organizations alike. With the rapid advancement of technology and the proliferation of online platforms, the need to safeguard personal information and maintain data confidentiality has become crucial. In this article, we will explore the significance of privacy in today&apos;s world and delve into the various reasons why it has become increasingly important. By understanding the implications of privacy breaches and adopting proactive measures, individuals and businesses can navigate the digital landscape while protecting their sensitive data.

## The Evolution of Privacy

### The Early Days of the Internet

In the early days of the internet, privacy concerns were relatively minimal. The internet was a nascent technology, and the concept of personal data being stored and shared online was not yet widespread. Individuals would navigate the online realm with a sense of anonymity, and there was a general lack of awareness regarding the potential risks associated with sharing personal information.

### The Rise of Social Media and Online Services

As the internet evolved, social media platforms and online services gained prominence. People began willingly sharing personal details, such as their locations, interests, and daily activities, on these platforms. Initially, the benefits of social connectivity and convenient online services outweighed the privacy concerns for many individuals.

### Privacy Breaches and Data Exploitation

However, the advent of privacy breaches and data exploitation incidents shed light on the vulnerability of personal information in the digital realm. High-profile cases involving the unauthorized access and misuse of user data by companies sparked public outrage and led to a shift in attitudes towards privacy. The Cambridge Analytica scandal, for instance, exposed how personal data could be weaponized for targeted advertising and manipulation.

## The Importance of Privacy

### Safeguarding Personal Information

Privacy plays a pivotal role in safeguarding personal information. With the increasing reliance on online platforms for various activities, including communication, banking, and shopping, individuals must ensure that their sensitive data remains confidential. By maintaining privacy, individuals can protect themselves from identity theft, financial fraud, and other forms of malicious activity.

### Preserving Autonomy and Freedom

Privacy is intricately linked to personal autonomy and freedom. When individuals have control over their personal information, they can make informed choices about its usage and dissemination. Privacy empowers individuals to express their opinions, explore diverse ideas, and engage in activities without the fear of surveillance or judgment. It fosters an environment that values personal autonomy and encourages the free exchange of thoughts and beliefs.

### Building Trust and Reputation

Privacy is essential for establishing trust between individuals, businesses, and institutions. When organizations prioritize data protection and privacy, they demonstrate their commitment to ethical practices and respect for their customers&apos; rights. Trustworthy businesses that prioritize privacy tend to attract more customers, as individuals feel confident in sharing their information and engaging with their products or services.

## The Implications of Ignoring Privacy

### Breach of Confidentiality

Failure to prioritize privacy can lead to severe consequences, including breaches of confidentiality. When personal information falls into the wrong hands, it can be exploited for various purposes, such as identity theft, fraud, or blackmail. Individuals may experience financial loss, reputational damage, and emotional distress as a result of privacy breaches.

### Erosion of Trust

Neglecting privacy can erode trust between businesses and consumers. When companies fail to protect customer data, it creates a sense of insecurity and disillusionment among their user base. Such breaches can result in customer attrition, negative brand perception, and potential legal repercussions.

### Legal and Regulatory Ramifications

In recent years, governments and

regulatory bodies worldwide have recognized the importance of privacy and enacted laws to protect individuals&apos; data. Organizations that disregard privacy regulations can face significant penalties and legal consequences. Compliance with privacy laws is not only a legal obligation but also a way to maintain a positive reputation and avoid potential fines.

## Strategies for Protecting Privacy

### Implementing Strong Security Measures

To safeguard privacy effectively, individuals and businesses must adopt robust security measures. This includes using strong passwords, enabling two-factor authentication, regularly updating software and applications, and encrypting sensitive data. By implementing these measures, the risk of unauthorized access and data breaches can be significantly reduced.

### Educating and Raising Awareness

Promoting privacy education and awareness is vital to empower individuals to protect their personal information. By educating people about the potential risks and best practices for privacy protection, they can make informed decisions when interacting with digital platforms. Educational initiatives can cover topics such as phishing awareness, secure online browsing, and privacy settings on social media.

### Embracing Privacy by Design

Privacy by Design is a framework that promotes privacy as the default setting in technological systems. By incorporating privacy considerations from the initial stages of product or service development, organizations can ensure that data protection is built into their offerings. This approach emphasizes proactive measures to prevent privacy breaches rather than reactive responses.

## Conclusion

In conclusion, privacy has evolved into a critical concern in our increasingly digital world. As individuals and organizations navigate the vast online landscape, prioritizing privacy is paramount to safeguard personal information, preserve autonomy, and build trust. The consequences of neglecting privacy can be severe, ranging from breaches of confidentiality to erosion of trust and legal ramifications. By adopting robust security measures, promoting awareness, and embracing Privacy by Design, we can foster a digital ecosystem that respects privacy rights and enables individuals to thrive in a secure and confidential environment.

To stay ahead in the digital realm, it is essential to prioritize privacy and adapt to the evolving landscape of data protection. By embracing privacy as a fundamental aspect of our digital lives, we can ensure that personal information remains secure and individuals can exercise their autonomy with confidence.

- 1. Tools for Privacy Protection:

  - Virtual Private Network (VPN): A VPN encrypts internet traffic, ensuring secure and private browsing. It masks your IP address and enhances online privacy. [Learn more about VPNs](https://www.cnet.com/how-to/what-is-a-vpn-why-do-you-need-one-and-how-do-they-work/).
  - Password Manager: Password managers securely store and generate strong passwords, reducing the risk of password-related vulnerabilities. They provide an extra layer of protection for your sensitive accounts. [Explore popular password managers](https://www.pcmag.com/picks/the-best-password-managers).

- 2. References:
  - Electronic Frontier Foundation (EFF): The EFF is a non-profit organization focused on defending civil liberties and privacy in the digital world. Their website offers valuable resources and updates on privacy-related issues. [Visit EFF&apos;s website](https://www.eff.org/).
  - General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR): The GDPR is a comprehensive privacy regulation implemented by the European Union. It sets standards for data protection and privacy rights. Understanding GDPR can provide insights into privacy best practices. [Learn more about GDPR](https://gdpr-info.eu/).

&lt;Aside type={&apos;positive&apos;} title={&apos;Thank you very much for reading!&apos;}&gt;
  Whilst I do write these for myself, it&apos;s also great if it helps other people
  out! So thank you for reading through and I hope I helped you out just a
  little bit. Become a
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sponsors/isyuricunha&quot;&gt; sponsor&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/Aside&gt;
</content:encoded>
            <author>
                <name>yuricunha</name>
                <email>hidden</email>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Latest Trends in Artificial Intelligence and Their Impact on Business.]]></title>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">The Latest Trends in Artificial Intelligence and Their Impact on Business.</guid>
            <id>https://localhost:3000/blogs/the-latest-trends-in-artificial-intelligence-and-their-impact-on-business</id>
            <updated>2023-05-16T08:20:27.751-03:00</updated>
            <description>The latest trends in artificial intelligence are shaping the future of businesses. Discover how this revolutionary technology is impacting different sectors and learn how your company can benefit from it. Read more about the latest trends in artificial intelligence and its impact on businesses in this informative article.</description>
            <image>/static/images/blog/artificial-intelligence/artificial-intelligence.jpg</image>
            <content:encoded>
&lt;Image
  alt={
    &apos;Artificial Intelligence (AI) has been rapidly advancing over the past few years, revolutionizing various industries and reshaping the way businesses operate. From predictive analytics to natural language processing, AI technologies are being employed to automate processes, enhance decision-making, and unlock valuable insights from vast amounts of data. In this article, we will explore the latest trends in artificial intelligence and delve into their significant impact on businesses across different sectors.&apos;
  }
  src={
    &apos;/static/images/blog/artificial-intelligence/artificial-intelligence.jpg&apos;
  }
  width={1905 / 2}
  height={957 / 2}
  layout=&quot;responsive&quot;
  blurDataURL={
    &apos;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAQAAAACCAIAAADwyuo0AAAACXBIWXMAAA7EAAAOxAGVKw4bAAAAIklEQVQImWNgYBDnFZCxsfc0tvJkCI/O+vP/f0tdhZK8CgBLPAfARKUieAAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==&apos;
  }
  placeholder=&quot;blur&quot;
/&gt;

# The Latest Trends in Artificial Intelligence and Their Impact on Business

## Introduction

Artificial Intelligence (AI) has been rapidly advancing over the past few years, revolutionizing various industries and reshaping the way businesses operate. From predictive analytics to natural language processing, AI technologies are being employed to automate processes, enhance decision-making, and unlock valuable insights from vast amounts of data. In this article, we will explore the latest trends in artificial intelligence and delve into their significant impact on businesses across different sectors.

## The Latest Trends in Artificial Intelligence and Their Impact on Business

Artificial intelligence is a dynamic field that continually evolves with new advancements. Let&apos;s take a closer look at some of the latest trends and their potential impact on business:

### 1. Machine Learning: Powering Intelligent Systems

Machine learning lies at the core of AI systems, enabling them to learn from data and improve their performance over time. With the latest advancements in machine learning algorithms and frameworks, businesses can develop intelligent systems that analyze complex datasets, recognize patterns, and make accurate predictions. This empowers organizations to enhance operational efficiency, personalize customer experiences, and optimize decision-making processes.

### 2. Natural Language Processing: Understanding Human Language

Natural Language Processing (NLP) has seen remarkable progress, allowing machines to understand and interpret human language. NLP algorithms can analyze text, speech, and even emotions, enabling businesses to extract valuable insights from unstructured data sources such as social media feeds, customer reviews, and support tickets. By leveraging NLP, organizations can improve customer service, automate content generation, and gain a deeper understanding of market trends.

### 3. Computer Vision: Transforming Visual Data

Computer vision technologies have advanced significantly, enabling machines to perceive and interpret visual data like never before. Through image and video analysis, businesses can automate tasks such as object recognition, visual inspection, and facial recognition. This opens up new possibilities for industries like healthcare, retail, and manufacturing, where visual data plays a crucial role in decision-making, quality control, and security.

### 4. Deep Learning: Unleashing the Power of Neural Networks

Deep learning, a subfield of machine learning, focuses on training artificial neural networks to perform complex tasks. This approach has revolutionized areas such as image and speech recognition, autonomous vehicles, and natural language understanding. With deep learning, businesses can achieve higher levels of accuracy and efficiency in tasks that require a deeper understanding of data patterns, enabling them to deliver more sophisticated products and services to their customers.

### 5. Explainable AI: Building Trust and Transparency

As AI becomes increasingly integrated into business processes, there is a growing need for transparency and explainability. Explainable AI aims to provide insights into how AI models make decisions, allowing businesses to understand the underlying logic and build trust with users and stakeholders. This trend is particularly relevant in industries with strict regulations, such as finance and healthcare, where explainability is crucial for compliance and risk management.

### 6. Edge Computing: Bringing AI to the Edge

Edge computing involves processing data closer to the source, reducing latency and enabling real-time decision-making. With the proliferation of Internet of Things (IoT) devices and the need for quick responses, edge computing has become an essential component of AI systems. By bringing AI algorithms to the edge, businesses can leverage the power of local processing, enabling faster insights, improved security, and enhanced privacy.

### 7. Autonomous Systems: Transforming Industries

Autonomous systems powered by AI are reshaping industries and introducing new opportunities for businesses. From self-driving cars to robotic process automation (RPA), autonomous systems have the potential to increase productivity, reduce costs, and enhance safety. However, the integration of autonomous systems also raises ethical and regulatory considerations that need to be addressed to ensure responsible and beneficial use.

### 8

. Augmented Analytics: Empowering Data-Driven Decisions

Augmented analytics combines AI and analytics to automate data preparation, analysis, and visualization tasks. By leveraging machine learning algorithms, businesses can uncover hidden patterns, generate actionable insights, and facilitate data-driven decision-making. Augmented analytics empowers organizations to extract maximum value from their data, enabling them to stay competitive in today&apos;s data-driven business landscape.

### 9. Robotic Process Automation: Streamlining Workflows

Robotic Process Automation (RPA) uses software robots or &quot;bots&quot; to automate repetitive and rule-based tasks. RPA can handle data entry, generate reports, and perform various administrative tasks, freeing up human resources to focus on more strategic activities. By implementing RPA, businesses can streamline workflows, reduce errors, and improve operational efficiency, leading to significant cost savings and enhanced productivity.

### 10. Cybersecurity: Battling Evolving Threats

As AI technology advances, so do the capabilities of cyber attackers. However, AI can also be utilized to strengthen cybersecurity defenses. AI-powered cybersecurity solutions can detect anomalies, identify potential threats, and respond to attacks in real time. By leveraging AI for cybersecurity, businesses can better protect their data, systems, and customer information from emerging threats and cybercriminal activities.

## Frequently Asked Questions (FAQs)

- 1. **Q:** How can businesses benefit from artificial intelligence?
     **A:** Artificial intelligence can bring numerous benefits to businesses, including improved operational efficiency, enhanced decision-making, personalized customer experiences, and automation of repetitive tasks.

- 2. **Q:** Are AI technologies accessible to small and medium-sized businesses?
     **A:** Yes, AI technologies are becoming more accessible and affordable for businesses of all sizes. Many cloud-based AI platforms and tools offer cost-effective solutions that can be easily integrated into existing business processes.

- 3. **Q:** Will AI replace human jobs?
     **A:** While AI may automate certain tasks, it also creates new job opportunities by enabling humans to focus on more complex and strategic work. AI is best seen as a tool to augment human capabilities rather than replace them entirely.

- 4. **Q:** What are the ethical considerations surrounding AI adoption?
     **A:** Ethical considerations in AI adoption include issues such as data privacy, algorithmic bias, transparency, and accountability. It is important for businesses to prioritize ethical frameworks and ensure responsible AI deployment.

- 5. **Q:** Can AI improve customer service?
     **A:** Absolutely. AI-powered chatbots and virtual assistants can provide 24/7 customer support, handle common inquiries, and personalize interactions, improving overall customer satisfaction.

- 6. **Q:** How can businesses prepare for AI adoption?
     **A:** To prepare for AI adoption, businesses should focus on building a data-driven culture, invest in AI talent, ensure data quality and accessibility, and establish clear goals and use cases for AI implementation.

## Conclusion

Artificial intelligence continues to evolve at a rapid pace, driving innovation and transforming industries across the globe. The latest trends in AI, such as machine learning, natural language processing, and computer vision, are revolutionizing the way businesses operate. By embracing these trends, organizations can unlock new opportunities, gain competitive advantages, and deliver superior products and services to their customers.

As businesses explore the potential of AI, it is crucial to address ethical considerations and ensure responsible deployment. Explainable AI provides transparency into AI decision-making processes, allowing businesses to understand the reasoning behind AI-driven outcomes. This not only helps build trust with users and stakeholders but also ensures compliance with regulations in industries such as finance and healthcare.

Edge computing has emerged as a significant trend in AI, especially with the rise of IoT devices. By processing data closer to the source, edge computing reduces latency and enables real-time decision-making. This is particularly valuable in scenarios where quick responses and low latency are critical, such as autonomous vehicles and smart manufacturing.

Autonomous systems, powered by AI, are transforming industries by increasing efficiency, reducing costs, and enhancing safety. From self-driving cars to robotic process automation, businesses can leverage autonomous systems to streamline workflows and improve productivity. However, the integration of autonomous systems also necessitates addressing ethical and regulatory considerations to ensure their responsible and beneficial use.

Augmented analytics combines the power of AI and analytics to automate data preparation, analysis, and visualization. By leveraging machine learning algorithms, businesses can uncover valuable insights, identify patterns, and make data-driven decisions. Augmented analytics enables organizations to extract maximum value from their data, gaining a competitive edge in today&apos;s data-centric business environment.

Robotic Process Automation (RPA) is another AI trend that streamlines workflows by automating repetitive tasks. RPA software robots or &quot;bots&quot; can handle data entry, generate reports, and perform administrative tasks, freeing up human resources for more strategic activities. The adoption of RPA leads to improved operational efficiency, reduced errors, and increased productivity.

With the advancement of AI, cybersecurity becomes an increasingly critical concern. However, AI can also be leveraged to strengthen cybersecurity defenses. AI-powered cybersecurity solutions can detect anomalies, identify potential threats, and respond in real time, bolstering the protection of data, systems, and customer information from evolving cyber threats.

In conclusion, the latest trends in artificial intelligence have a profound impact on businesses across various sectors. From machine learning and natural language processing to computer vision and explainable AI, these trends enable businesses to automate processes, make data-driven decisions, and gain competitive advantages. The integration of AI technologies brings opportunities for improved efficiency, personalized customer experiences, and enhanced productivity. However, ethical considerations, responsible deployment, and cybersecurity measures should be prioritized to ensure the benefits of AI are harnessed while mitigating potential risks. Embracing these trends and leveraging AI&apos;s potential will empower businesses to thrive in the ever-evolving digital landscape.

&lt;Aside type={&apos;positive&apos;} title={&apos;Thank you very much for reading!&apos;}&gt;
  Whilst I do write these for myself, it&apos;s also great if it helps other people
  out! So thank you for reading through and I hope I helped you out just a
  little bit. Become a
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sponsors/isyuricunha&quot;&gt; sponsor&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/Aside&gt;
</content:encoded>
            <author>
                <name>yuricunha</name>
                <email>hidden</email>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Pomodoro Technique: A Simple and Effective Way to Improve Focus.]]></title>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">The Pomodoro Technique: A Simple and Effective Way to Improve Focus.</guid>
            <id>https://localhost:3000/blogs/pomodoro-tech</id>
            <updated>2023-05-14T08:55:27.751-03:00</updated>
            <description>The article emphasizes the importance of planning and organization to achieve productivity and success in both work and personal life. It also provides references to related resources for further reading.</description>
            <image>/static/images/blog/pomodoro-tech/pomodoro-banner.jpg</image>
            <content:encoded>
&lt;Image
  alt={&apos;The Pomodoro Technique: A Simple and Effective Way to Improve Focus.&apos;}
  src={&apos;/static/images/blog/pomodoro-tech/pomodoro-banner.jpg&apos;}
  width={1905 / 2}
  height={957 / 2}
  layout=&quot;responsive&quot;
  blurDataURL={
    &apos;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAQAAAACCAIAAADwyuo0AAAACXBIWXMAAA7EAAAOxAGVKw4bAAAAIklEQVQImWNgYBDnFZCxsfc0tvJkCI/O+vP/f0tdhZK8CgBLPAfARKUieAAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==&apos;
  }
  placeholder=&quot;blur&quot;
/&gt;

# How to Improve Your Focus with the Pomodoro Technique

Are you tired of getting easily distracted while working or studying? Do you struggle to maintain your focus for extended periods of time? If so, you may be interested in the Pomodoro Technique, a time-management strategy that can help you improve your focus and productivity.

## What is the Pomodoro Technique?

The Pomodoro Technique is a time-management method developed by Francesco Cirillo in the late 1980s. It involves breaking your work or study time into 25-minute intervals, called Pomodoros, separated by short breaks. After completing four Pomodoros, you take a longer break of 15-30 minutes.

The idea behind the technique is that by working in short bursts, you can maintain your focus and avoid burnout. It also helps you stay on track by providing a clear structure for your study or work sessions.

## How to Use the Pomodoro Technique

To use the Pomodoro Technique, follow these steps:

- Choose a task you want to work on.
- Set a timer for 25 minutes and start working on the task.
- When the timer goes off, take a five-minute break.
- Repeat steps 2 and 3 three more times.
- After completing four Pomodoros, take a longer break of 15-30 minutes.
- Start again from step 1.

During your break time, it&apos;s essential to take your mind off work entirely. Stretch, walk around, grab a snack, or do anything that helps you relax. The goal is to give your brain a break so that you can return to your task with renewed energy and focus.

## Benefits of the Pomodoro Technique

The Pomodoro Technique offers several benefits, including:

- Increased productivity: By breaking your work into manageable intervals, you can avoid burnout and maintain your focus throughout the day.
- Improved time management: The Pomodoro Technique helps you prioritize your tasks, enabling you to make the most of your time.
- Reduced procrastination: The structure of the technique makes it easy to get started on tasks, reducing the temptation to procrastinate.
- Enhanced focus: By working in short bursts, you can concentrate better and avoid distractions.
- Reduced stress: The Pomodoro Technique helps you avoid burnout, reducing stress levels.

## Resources for Using the Pomodoro Technique

If you&apos;re interested in trying the Pomodoro Technique, several resources can help you get started. Here are a few helpful links:

- [Pomodoro Timer](https://tomato-timer.com/): A simple online timer that can help you keep track of your Pomodoros.
- [Focus@Will](https://www.focusatwill.com/): A music service that provides background music designed to help you concentrate.
- [Pomodoro Technique Illustrated](https://www.amazon.com/Pomodoro-Technique-Illustrated-Pragmatic-Life/dp/1934356506): A book by Francesco Cirillo that provides a detailed guide to the technique.

In conclusion, the Pomodoro Technique is a simple but effective way to improve your focus and productivity. By breaking your work into manageable intervals and taking regular breaks, you can maintain your concentration and avoid burnout. Give it a try and see how it can benefit you!

&lt;Aside type={&apos;positive&apos;} title={&apos;Thank you very much for reading!&apos;}&gt;
  Whilst I do write these for myself, it&apos;s also great if it helps other people
  out! So thank you for reading through and I hope I helped you out just a
  little bit. Become a
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sponsors/isyuricunha&quot;&gt; sponsor&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/Aside&gt;
</content:encoded>
            <author>
                <name>yuricunha</name>
                <email>hidden</email>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to plan a productive day.]]></title>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">How to plan a productive day.</guid>
            <id>https://localhost:3000/blogs/how-to-plan-a-productive-day</id>
            <updated>2023-03-05T11:50:27.751-03:00</updated>
            <description>The article emphasizes the importance of planning and organization to achieve productivity and success in both work and personal life. It also provides references to related resources for further reading.</description>
            <image>/static/images/blog/how-to-plan-a-productive-day/have-a-productive-day.jpg</image>
            <content:encoded>
&lt;Image
  alt={
    &apos;This article provides tips and strategies to help you plan a productive day.&apos;
  }
  src={
    &apos;/static/images/blog/how-to-plan-a-productive-day/have-a-productive-day.jpg&apos;
  }
  width={1905 / 2}
  height={957 / 2}
  layout=&quot;responsive&quot;
  blurDataURL={
    &apos;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAQAAAACCAIAAADwyuo0AAAACXBIWXMAAA7EAAAOxAGVKw4bAAAAIklEQVQImWNgYBDnFZCxsfc0tvJkCI/O+vP/f0tdhZK8CgBLPAfARKUieAAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==&apos;
  }
  placeholder=&quot;blur&quot;
/&gt;

# How to Plan a Productive Day

Having a productive day is all about setting yourself up for success. With a bit of planning and organization, you can make the most of your time and accomplish your goals. Here are some tips to help you plan a productive day:

## Start with a To-Do List

Before you start your day, make a list of the tasks you need to complete. This will help you stay focused and ensure that you don&apos;t forget anything important. Prioritize your tasks based on their urgency and importance, and try to tackle the most difficult or time-consuming ones first.

## Break Up Your Day

Trying to work for hours on end without taking breaks can lead to burnout and decreased productivity. Instead, break up your day into smaller, manageable chunks. Work for a set amount of time, and then take a short break to stretch, move around, or do something enjoyable. This will help you stay energized and focused throughout the day.

## Minimize Distractions

Distractions can quickly derail your productivity and make it difficult to stay on task. To minimize distractions, turn off your phone notifications and email alerts, and close any unnecessary tabs on your computer. If possible, work in a quiet space where you won&apos;t be interrupted by noise or other people.

## Take Care of Yourself

Taking care of your physical and mental health is crucial for maintaining productivity. Make sure you&apos;re getting enough sleep, eating well, and staying hydrated throughout the day. Take breaks to stretch or do some light exercise, and prioritize activities that help you relax and unwind, like reading or meditating.

## Review Your Progress

At the end of the day, take a few minutes to review your progress and reflect on what went well and what could be improved. Use this information to adjust your plan for the next day, and celebrate the small wins along the way.

With these tips in mind, you&apos;ll be well on your way to planning a productive day that helps you accomplish your goals and feel more fulfilled in your work and personal life.

---

References:

- [The Science of Productivity](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lHfjvYzr-3g)
- [The Power of Habit: Why We Do What We Do in Life and Business](https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12609433-the-power-of-habit)
- [The 7 Habits of Highly Effective People](https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/36072.The_7_Habits_of_Highly_Effective_People)

&lt;Aside type={&apos;positive&apos;} title={&apos;Thank you very much for reading!&apos;}&gt;
  Whilst I do write these for myself, it&apos;s also great if it helps other people
  out! So thank you for reading through and I hope I helped you out just a
  little bit. Become a
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sponsors/isyuricunha&quot;&gt; sponsor&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/Aside&gt;
</content:encoded>
            <author>
                <name>yuricunha</name>
                <email>hidden</email>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Becoming a junior front-end developer: A comprehensive guide with tips, codes, and resources]]></title>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">Becoming a junior front-end developer: A comprehensive guide with tips, codes, and resources</guid>
            <id>https://localhost:3000/blogs/roadmap-front-end</id>
            <updated>2023-02-05T19:40:27.751-03:00</updated>
            <description>This article is your ultimate guide to becoming a Junior Front-End Developer. With tips, resources, and step-by-step guidance, this comprehensive guide will help you achieve your career goals and become a skilled Front-End Developer.</description>
            <image>/static/images/blog/junior-front-end/front-end-roadmap.jpg</image>
            <content:encoded>
&lt;Image
  alt={&apos;A comprehensive junior front-end guide with tips, codes, and resources&apos;}
  src={&apos;/static/images/blog/junior-front-end/front-end-roadmap.jpg&apos;}
  width={1905 / 2}
  height={957 / 2}
  layout=&quot;responsive&quot;
  blurDataURL={
    &apos;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAQAAAACCAIAAADwyuo0AAAACXBIWXMAAA7EAAAOxAGVKw4bAAAAIklEQVQImWNgYBDnFZCxsfc0tvJkCI/O+vP/f0tdhZK8CgBLPAfARKUieAAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==&apos;
  }
  placeholder=&quot;blur&quot;
/&gt;

# Roadmap to Becoming a Junior Front-End Developer

## Introduction

Becoming a front-end developer requires a solid understanding of HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, and a lot of practice. Front-end developers design and build user interfaces for websites and applications, and must have strong attention to detail, problem-solving skills, and an eye for good design.

Here&apos;s a roadmap to help you on your journey to becoming a junior front-end developer.

## Step 1: Learn HTML and CSS

HTML (HyperText Markup Language) and CSS (Cascading Style Sheets) are the building blocks of the web. HTML provides the structure and content of a web page, while CSS provides the styling and layout.

To get started, check out the following resources:

- W3Schools: A great beginner&apos;s guide to HTML and CSS.
  https://www.w3schools.com/html/
  https://www.w3schools.com/css/
- Codecademy: An interactive learning platform that offers courses on HTML and CSS.
  https://www.codecademy.com/learn/introduction-to-html
  https://www.codecademy.com/learn/introduction-to-css

You can also check out these fun HTML and CSS projects to put your skills to the test:

- Create a personal website
- Build a CSS clock
- Design a responsive landing page

## Step 2: Learn JavaScript

JavaScript is a programming language that is used to add interactivity to websites and web applications.

To learn JavaScript, check out the following resources:

- W3Schools: A great beginner&apos;s guide to JavaScript.
  https://www.w3schools.com/js/
- Codecademy: An interactive learning platform that offers a course on JavaScript.
  https://www.codecademy.com/learn/introduction-to-javascript

You can also work on these fun JavaScript projects to practice your skills:

- Create a to-do list app
- Build a calculator
- Create a random quote generator

## Step 3: Practice and Build Projects

Now that you have a solid understanding of HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, it&apos;s time to put your skills to the test by building projects. Not only will this help you solidify your understanding of the technologies, but it will also give you a portfolio to showcase to potential employers.

Some project ideas to get you started:

- Create a weather app that displays the current weather for a given location
- Build a simple e-commerce site
- Create a game using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript

## Step 4: Stay Up-to-Date with the Latest Technologies

The world of front-end development is constantly evolving, with new technologies and best practices emerging all the time. To stay ahead of the game, make sure to stay up-to-date with the latest developments in the field.

Follow industry leaders on social media, subscribe to front-end development newsletters, and attend meetups and conferences to stay current.

## Step 5: Network and Build Relationships

Networking and building relationships within the front-end development community is an important part of your journey to becoming a junior front-end developer.

Join online communities like Reddit&apos;s r/webdev, attend meetups and conferences, and reach out to other front-end developers for advice and mentorship.

## Conclusion

By following the steps outlined in this roadmap, you will be well on your way to becoming a successful Junior Front-end Developer. Remember to always stay curious and continue learning, as the tech industry is constantly evolving. With dedication and hard work, you can turn your passion for coding into a fulfilling career. Good luck on your journey!

If you have any questions or would like further resources, feel free to reach out. You can also check out the following references for additional information and inspiration:

- [W3Schools](https://www.w3schools.com/)
- [FreeCodeCamp](https://www.freecodecamp.org/)
- [MDN Web Docs](https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/)
- [CSS-Tricks](https://css-tricks.com/)
- [JavaScript.info](https://javascript.info/)

And finally, here&apos;s a fun code snippet to break the ice:

```
function joke() {
  console.log(&quot;Why was the computer cold? Because it left its Windows open.&quot;);
}
joke();
```

&lt;Aside type={&apos;positive&apos;} title={&apos;Thank you very much for reading!&apos;}&gt;
  Whilst I do write these for myself, it&apos;s also great if it helps other people
  out! So thank you for reading through and I hope I helped you out just a
  little bit. Become a
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sponsors/isyuricunha&quot;&gt; sponsor&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/Aside&gt;
</content:encoded>
            <author>
                <name>yuricunha</name>
                <email>hidden</email>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What is the SQL Server Database?]]></title>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">What is the SQL Server Database?</guid>
            <id>https://localhost:3000/blogs/what-is-sql-server-and-sql</id>
            <updated>2023-01-05T09:20:27.751-03:00</updated>
            <description>Lets talk about my favorite database.</description>
            <image>/static/images/blog/50-days-of-meditation/50-days-of-meditation.jpg</image>
            <content:encoded>
&lt;Image
  alt={&apos;SQL Server and examples.&apos;}
  src={&apos;/static/images/blog/what-is-sql-server-and-sql/sql-example.png&apos;}
  width={1905 / 2}
  height={957 / 2}
  layout=&quot;responsive&quot;
  blurDataURL={
    &apos;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAQAAAACCAIAAADwyuo0AAAACXBIWXMAAA7EAAAOxAGVKw4bAAAAIklEQVQImWNgYBDnFZCxsfc0tvJkCI/O+vP/f0tdhZK8CgBLPAfARKUieAAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==&apos;
  }
  placeholder=&quot;blur&quot;
/&gt;

# What is the SQL Server Database?

The SQL Server Database is a relational database management system produced by Microsoft. It is used to store and manage large amounts of data, including structured and unstructured data. SQL Server offers a wide range of features to ensure the security, availability, and integrity of stored data, as well as to ensure system performance and scalability.

There are several versions of SQL Server available, including SQL Server Express, SQL Server Standard, and SQL Server Enterprise. Each of these versions offers a different set of features and is suitable for different types of use.

To work with SQL Server, it is necessary to know the Structured Query Language (SQL). SQL is the standard language for working with relational databases and is used to create, query, and modify the data stored in the database.

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

# What is the Structured Query Language (famous SQL)?

Structured Query Language (SQL) is a programming language used to manage and manipulate data stored in relational databases. It is the standard language for working with relational databases and is used to create, query, and modify the data stored in the database.

SQL is a declarative language, which means that it is used to describe what needs to be done, rather than specifying how it should be done. This allows the database management system (DBMS) to optimize the execution of SQL queries and ensure efficient use of system resources.

SQL is used to perform a wide range of tasks, including creating and modifying tables and indices, inserting and updating data, and retrieving data from the database. It is also used to define the structure and relationships of the data within the database, as well as to set permissions and controls for users.

SQL is a powerful and versatile language that is widely used in a variety of industries, including business, finance, healthcare, and government. It is an essential tool for database administrators and developers, and is also used by data analysts and data scientists to extract, transform, and load data for analysis and reporting purposes.

There are several dialects of SQL, including MySQL, Oracle, and Microsoft SQL Server, each with its own unique features and syntax. However, the core concepts and principles of SQL are the same across all dialects, making it a language that is easy to learn and widely applicable.

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

# Examples of SQL Queries

Here are some examples of SQL queries that can be run on the SQL Server Database:

## _Select Query_

- The following query selects all fields from the &quot;Customers&quot; table where the &quot;City&quot; field is equal to &quot;São Paulo&quot;:

```sql
SELECT * FROM Customers WHERE City = &apos;São Paulo&apos;;
```

&lt;br /&gt;

## _Insert Data_

- The following query inserts a new record into the &quot;Customers&quot; table:

```sql
INSERT INTO Customers (Name, Address, City) VALUES (&apos;João da Silva&apos;, &apos;Rua das Flores, 123&apos;, &apos;São Paulo&apos;);
```

&lt;br /&gt;

## _Update Data_

- The following query updates the &quot;Address&quot; field of the record with ID 1 in the &quot;Customers&quot; table:

```sql
UPDATE Customers SET Address = &apos;Rua das Oliveiras, 456&apos; WHERE ID = 1;
```

&lt;br /&gt;

## _Delete Data_

- The following query deletes the record with ID 1 from the &quot;Customers&quot; table:

```sql
DELETE FROM Customers WHERE ID = 1;
```

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

# Two simple examples

&lt;br /&gt;

## First example

&lt;br /&gt;

&gt; You are the database administrator for a small customer database. You need to add a new customer record with the following information:

&lt;br /&gt;

- Name: &quot;John Smith&quot;
- Address: &quot;123 Main Street&quot;
- City: &quot;New York&quot;

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

## _Solution_

&lt;br /&gt;

- To add the new customer record, you can use the following SQL query:

```sql
INSERT INTO Customers (Name, Address, City) VALUES (&apos;John Smith&apos;, &apos;123 Main Street&apos;, &apos;New York&apos;);
```

&lt;br /&gt;

_This query will insert a new record into the &quot;Customers&quot; table with the specified name, address, and city._

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

## Second example

&lt;br /&gt;

&gt; You are the database administrator for a product inventory database. You need to update the quantity of a product with the ID &quot;12345&quot; to 10.

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

## _Solution_

&lt;br /&gt;

- You are the database administrator for a product inventory database. You need to update the quantity of a product with the ID &quot;12345&quot; to 10.

```sql
UPDATE Products SET Quantity = 10 WHERE ID = 12345;
```

&lt;br /&gt;

_This query will update the &quot;Quantity&quot; field of the product with the ID &quot;12345&quot; to the value 10._

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

# Complex example

Here is a complex example and solution involving the SQL Server Database:

&gt; You are the database administrator for a large online retailer. The company has a database with several tables storing information about customers, orders, and products. The database is used to track customer information, process orders, and generate reports.

&gt; One of the company&apos;s sales managers has requested a report showing the total sales and number of orders for each customer, broken down by product category. The report should show the data for the past year, and should be sorted by total sales in descending order.

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

## _Solution_

&lt;br /&gt;

- To generate the requested report, you can use the following SQL query:

```sql
SELECT c.Name AS &apos;Customer&apos;,
       SUM(o.Total) AS &apos;Total Sales&apos;,
       COUNT(o.ID) AS &apos;Number of Orders&apos;,
       p.Category AS &apos;Product Category&apos;
FROM Customers c
INNER JOIN Orders o ON c.ID = o.CustomerID
INNER JOIN Products p ON o.ProductID = p.ID
WHERE o.Date BETWEEN &apos;2022-01-01&apos; AND &apos;2022-12-31&apos;
GROUP BY c.Name, p.Category
ORDER BY &apos;Total Sales&apos; DESC;
```

&lt;br /&gt;

_This query will select the customer name, total sales, number of orders, and product category for all orders placed within the specified date range. It will then group the results by customer name and product category, and will sort the results by total sales in descending order. The resulting report will show the total sales and number of orders for each customer, broken down by product category._

&lt;br /&gt;

&gt; I hope the examples have helped you.

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

###### _Here are some additional reference links that you might find helpful in learning more about SQL Server Database and the SQL language:_

- The SQL Server homepage: https://www.microsoft.com/sql-server/

- The SQL Server documentation: https://docs.microsoft.com/sql/

- The SQL tutorial: https://www.w3schools.com/sql/

- The MySQL reference guide: https://dev.mysql.com/doc/refman/8.0/en/

- The Oracle SQL tutorial: https://docs.oracle.com/en/database/oracle/oracle-database/19/lnpls/index.html

&gt; I hope these additional references and syntax are helpful to you.

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;Aside type={&apos;positive&apos;} title={&apos;Thank you very much for reading!&apos;}&gt;
  Whilst I do write these for myself, it&apos;s also great if it helps other people
  out! So thank you for reading through and I hope I helped you out just a
  little bit. Become a
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sponsors/isyuricunha&quot;&gt; sponsor&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/Aside&gt;
</content:encoded>
            <author>
                <name>yuricunha</name>
                <email>hidden</email>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Uses.]]></title>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">Uses.</guid>
            <id>https://localhost:3000/blogs/tools-and-products-that-i-use-everyday</id>
            <updated>2022-10-31T18:26:30.741-03:00</updated>
            <description>Tools and products that I use everyday.</description>
            <image>/static/images/blog/tools-and-products-that-i-use-everyday/tools-and-products-that-i-use-everyday.jpg</image>
            <content:encoded>
&lt;Image
  alt={&apos;Tools and products that I use everyday.&apos;}
  src={
    &apos;/static/images/blog/tools-and-products-that-i-use-everyday/tools-and-products-that-i-use-everyday.jpg&apos;
  }
  width={1905 / 2}
  height={957 / 2}
  layout=&quot;responsive&quot;
  blurDataURL={
    &apos;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAQAAAACCAIAAADwyuo0AAAACXBIWXMAAA7EAAAOxAGVKw4bAAAAIklEQVQImWNgYBDnFZCxsfc0tvJkCI/O+vP/f0tdhZK8CgBLPAfARKUieAAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==&apos;
  }
  placeholder=&quot;blur&quot;
/&gt;

Tools come and go. But some things just stick. In the list below I grouped all the tools that I use for work and at home. If you have questions about anything on this list, feel free to [message me](mailto:isyuricunha@duck.com).

## Productivity

**[Alfred](https://www.alfredapp.com/)**

Spotlight on steroids. I use Alfred at least 20 times per day to open apps, access my clipboard, and start small workflows (e.g refresh my Wi-Fi). I happily paid for the Powerpack and recommend Alfred to everyone who works on a mac.

**[Dynalist](https://dynalist.io/)**

Dynalist lets you outline everything that crosses your mind. Think bullet-points where you can go as deep as you want and any bullet-point can be seen as an individual page. I use it as my note-taking app, occasional journal and for writing.

**[Tripmode](https://www.tripmode.ch/)**

I was always afraid to use too much data when I worked on my hotspot. Not anymore. With Tripmode I can easily manage which apps have internet access and see how much I used in one session.

**[Rescuetime](https://www.rescuetime.com/)**

Rescuetime runs in the background on my Mac and Android and tracks my screen time. I&apos;m often too afraid to look into the statistics. The calendar integration is great for a quick overview.

**[LastPass](https://www.lastpass.com/)**

LastPass is the biggest time saver. I use it both personally and at work to manage passwords, and store confidential data. (e.g social identification number). I would be completely lost without this app.

## Design

**[SIP](https://sipapp.io/)**

SIP is a beautiful color picker. I only use the colour picker feature, but the rest of the app is pretty nice too. My custom shortcut is `⌥ + SHIFT + -`.

**[Framer](https://www.framer.com/)**

Framer lets you design and code in one project. This means that prototypes can use real data, be interactive and much more detailed. I find this extremely appealing and try to use Framer whenever I can. The only drawback at the moment is the missing web version.

**[Figma](https://www.figma.com/)**

Figma is the standard for collaborative design. It&apos;s intuitive to use, has a plugin ecosystem and the performance is unmatched. I use it when I need to work with other designers or developers in one file.

**[Adobe Creative Cloud](https://www.adobe.com/creativecloud.html)**

I share a monthly Adobe Cloud subscription with my girlfriend. The only apps I use are Lightroom, Photoshop and Illustrator. I think that most of the Adobe apps are clunky, too powerful and I tend to get frustrated working with them.

**[Canva](https://www.canva.com/)**

Canva is a simple but feature-rich web app for quick designs. There is a massive template library for every format you can think about. This makes it possible to quickly design something that just looks good. I use Canva for social media posts, print design and random things.

## Development

**[VS Code](https://code.visualstudio.com/)**

VS code became very popular when I started to code at the end of 2018. And that for a reason. The app is quick as a flash and offers many extensions by the community. I do all my coding in VS Code and have nothing to complain about.

**[Netlify](https://www.netlify.com/)**

I&apos;m no expert when it comes to hosting and back-end topics. That&apos;s why I love Netlify. It just works and helps me to get back into what I feel comfortable with. I&apos;m on the free tier and use Netlify for hosting my static projects. I also have a nice pair of socks by Netlify.

**[Namecheap](https://www.namecheap.com/)**

I bought my first domain with Namecheap and never made the switch. There is probably a better domain registrar out there, but I never took the courage to switch. If you think I need to make the jump, please write to me.

**[GitHub](https://github.com/)**

All of my code lives on GitHub. You can see the code for this website [here](https://github.com/wirtzdan/new-website). If you don&apos;t understand what&apos;s going on, feel free to write to me. I would be happy to help.

**[iTerm 2](https://iterm2.com/)**

I use iTerm as my terminal client in combination with zsh. I honestly have no clue why I need this other than that I have nice themes here.

**[ImageOptim](https://imageoptim.com/mac)**

ImageOptim is a hidden gem. The small app can easily bulk compress 100 images at once and often reduce file-size by half. I use it in combination with Preview to cut, scale and compress all of my images for web usage.

## Tech

**[Peak Design Everyday Backpack](https://www.peakdesign.com/products/everyday-backpack)**

Peak Design is one of the brands which I would jump into the fire with. I hesitated at first to buy the backpack, but it was worth every penny. I&apos;m running around with this backpack every day and use it for work, travel, groceries, and photography.

**[MacBook Pro (15-inch, 2017)](https://www.apple.com/shop/buy-mac/macbook-pro)**

My on-the-go workstation and backpack companion. I spend the majority of my time with this device and love the convenience it gives me. Pricy, but worth the investment.

**[Fujifilm X-T10](https://www.fujifilmusa.com/products/digital_cameras/x/fujifilm_x_t10/)**

I have a special connection to this camera since I bought it at the beginning of university. It&apos;s small, clicky and always impresses me with the image quality. I constantly switch between two prime lenses (23mm F2 &amp; 50mm F2).

**[Magic Mouse 2](https://www.apple.com/de/shop/product/MLA02Z/A/magic-mouse-2-silber)**

Apple Magic Mouse 2 that I snatched on eBay for 30€. Works like a charm on any surface. The only complain that I have is that it needs batteries. I often forget to pack an extra pack when I&apos;m on the road.

**[Ergonomic Laptop Stand](https://www.amazon.de/dp/B01N99IGMQ/ref=sr_1_5?crid=2XJA82MXCVRRC&amp;keywords=mobiler+laptop+st%C3%A4nder&amp;qid=1573384409&amp;sprefix=mobile+laptop%2Caps%2C200&amp;sr=8-5)**

This is the smallest and most lightweight laptop stand that I found. Always attached to the side of my backpack and fast to set up.

**[Logitech K380](https://www.logitech.com/en-us/product/multi-device-keyboard-k380)**

This keyboard [fits perfectly](https://twitter.com/wirtzdan/status/1193482720615243776?s=19) into the top department of my backpack. That alone is very satisfying. In combination with my laptop-stand, mouse and backpack I have a very flexible workstation.
</content:encoded>
            <author>
                <name>yuricunha</name>
                <email>hidden</email>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[50 days of meditation.]]></title>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">50 days of meditation.</guid>
            <id>https://localhost:3000/blogs/waking-up-app</id>
            <updated>2022-10-26T16:20:27.751-03:00</updated>
            <description>Reflections on 50 days of meditation.</description>
            <image>/static/images/blog/50-days-of-meditation/50-days-of-meditation.jpg</image>
            <content:encoded>
&lt;Image
  alt={&apos;50 days of meditation.&apos;}
  src={&apos;/static/images/blog/50-days-of-meditation/50-days-of-meditation.jpg&apos;}
  width={1905 / 2}
  height={957 / 2}
  layout=&quot;responsive&quot;
  blurDataURL={
    &apos;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAQAAAACCAIAAADwyuo0AAAACXBIWXMAAA7EAAAOxAGVKw4bAAAAIklEQVQImWNgYBDnFZCxsfc0tvJkCI/O+vP/f0tdhZK8CgBLPAfARKUieAAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==&apos;
  }
  placeholder=&quot;blur&quot;
/&gt;

Two months ago my mind wasn&apos;t in the best shape. My thoughts were always drifting in different directions. When I woke up once, I immediately started to think about my daily agenda and how I should handle an important call at work. Even though I even prepared breakfast or brushed my teeth.

My mind felt a little bit like a bar fight in a western movie. A scene of chaos, with things flying around in all directions. Something had to change.

In the past, I made good experience with meditation. While I was studying I was introduced to meditation by listening to the Tim Ferris podcast. I hesitated at first. Meditation always appeared to me as something for monks, spiritual people and hippies. But when I started with practice it helped me to calm down from the hectic life a university student. When I had the feeling that I attained more calmness, I somehow stopped to meditate.

Something I always wanted to try was the [Waking Up](https://www.wakingup.com) app by Sam Harris. Sam Harris is a philosopher, neuroscientist and host of the [Making Sense](https://samharris.org/podcast/) podcast. I always admired his way of speaking. He presents often complex topics in simple, yet powerful clarity. And someone who is able to speak clearly also thinks clearly. One can&apos;t go without the other.

Sam Harris also has a lot of experience in speaking and writing, but he is also meditating for more than 30 years. That sparked my interest to take a look into his app and try out the introduction course for 50 days. In this article, I sum up some of my learnings and observations.

## 1. Ten minutes can go a long way

As part of the introduction course, I always meditated for roughly ten minutes. Sometimes even that felt long and daunting. But most of the time, the sessions end quicker than I expected.
For me, that timeframe, felt exactly right, because you can always squeeze in ten minutes. Even if you are busy with work, tired of sport or travelling for the whole day.

## 2. Meditating with the morning sun

Meditating in the morning was the key for me to **stay consistent with the practice**. Not because the morning has a better effect per see. But I have the most control over how I spend my mornings and I can&apos;t say this about evenings. Sometimes I stay home and go to bed earlier, but on another day I could go out with friends and come back later in the night. Meditating in the mornings helped me to stick to daily habit and when I forget it in the morning, I was still able to do it throughout the day or in the evening.

## 3. You don&apos;t need a silent spot to meditate

The meditations in the introduction course where guided meditation. Sam Harris provided clear instructions and often explained the reason behind the practice. But sometimes he spoke a lot and that made it harder for me to relax and meditate.

In one of the lessons, he addressed this, because many students give him that feedback. He explains that meditation isn&apos;t something you should only do when you are in a quiet environment. Meditation is about being mindful and in the best case this is a state of living. Rather than a ten minutes window once a day.

That made total sense for me and I started to **meditate in more lifelike environments**. Sometimes the dishwasher was going, the window was open. The challenge of staying undistracted in loud environments was a great challenge to practice mindfulness.

## 4. Who is the Thinker?

Have you ever asked yourself if you can pick your next thought? Maybe you think this is a stupid question, but observe your mind for a minute.

**If you are like me, thoughts often just appear.** Similar to how bubbles appear on the lake, thoughts appear in conscious.

That&apos;s also why it&apos;s so hard to sit still and think about nothing for five minutes. It sounds simple, but in practice it&apos;s impossible. With effort you can keep your mind focused on the breath for 30 seconds, but once your attention slips your mind goes on a free ride.

From there, thoughts will just appear in conscious. Maybe because you heard a familiar sound, or remembered to do something, but sometimes also completely randomly. Even if you tell yourself you are the thinker in your head, the reality tells a different story.

## 5. Quality of mind

The most profound insight for me was that the quality of my mind is at the base of every experience I have and the contribution I make to the world.

On days where I had a good meditation session, I felt more aware, productive and fulfilled. This was most visible at work, where I often was forced to listen carefully to clients and where everything has to make sense that I verbalise. Before meditating with Waking up, I sometimes zoned out of conversations, got distracted and felt guilty afterwards.

Of course, this still happens. **Getting distracted is the natural state of the mind.** But now that I meditate frequently, it happens less and for me, this improved what Sam Harris often calls the quality of mind.

## What&apos;s next

In the beginning, my mind was all over the place. But now I&apos;m feeling much more mindful with my thoughts and experiences throughout the day. Meditating for the last 50 days showed me what difference it can make.

Therefore I want to continue on the journey and go regularly to my mental fitness gym. Which for me means to sit down at the couch, drink a tea and do nothing for ten minutes per day.

_PS: If you want to give the Waking up a try, here is an [invitation link](https://share.wakingup.com/327932) which will unlock the app for you for a month. I don&apos;t get anything for it, but as it was helpful for me, so can it be for you._

&lt;Aside type={&apos;positive&apos;} title={&apos;Thank you very much for reading!&apos;}&gt;
  Whilst I do write these for myself, it&apos;s also great if it helps other people
  out! So thank you for reading through and I hope I helped you out just a
  little bit. Become a
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sponsors/isyuricunha&quot;&gt; sponsor&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/Aside&gt;
</content:encoded>
            <author>
                <name>yuricunha</name>
                <email>hidden</email>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Coisas que eu gostaria que tivessem me dito quando entrei na faculdade de TI.]]></title>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">Coisas que eu gostaria que tivessem me dito quando entrei na faculdade de TI.</guid>
            <id>https://localhost:3000/blogs/coisas-que-eu-gostaria-que-tivessem-me-dito-quando-entrei-na-faculdade-de-ti</id>
            <updated>2022-08-12</updated>
            <description>TI é tão vasto quanto medicina.</description>
            <image>/static/images/blog/coisas-que-eu-gostaria-que-tivessem-me-dito-quando-entrei-na-faculdade-de-ti/banner.png</image>
            <content:encoded>
&lt;Image
  alt={&apos;TI é tão vasto quanto medicina.&apos;}
  src={
    &apos;/static/images/blog/coisas-que-eu-gostaria-que-tivessem-me-dito-quando-entrei-na-faculdade-de-ti/banner.png&apos;
  }
  width={1905 / 2}
  height={957 / 2}
  layout=&quot;responsive&quot;
  blurDataURL={
    &apos;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAQAAAACCAIAAADwyuo0AAAACXBIWXMAAA7EAAAOxAGVKw4bAAAAIklEQVQImWNgYBDnFZCxsfc0tvJkCI/O+vP/f0tdhZK8CgBLPAfARKUieAAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==&apos;
  }
  placeholder=&quot;blur&quot;
/&gt;

Semestre começando na faculdade e vários calouros com dúvidas no grupo do Telegram. Isso lembrou-me das minhas próprias dúvidas quando comecei a minha primeira graduação e das coisas que gostaria de saber naquela época.

**1 - Inglês**

A esmagadora maioria das documentações está em inglês e um site de tradução nem sempre irá te ajudar, em alguns casos ele irá traduzir termos técnicos que não deveriam ser traduzidos ou possuem outro significado fora do contexto de informática.

- Ler em inglês: Ter uma boa leitura em inglês já é 50% do necessário.
- Escrever em inglês: Vai te ajudar muito a tirar dúvidas em fóruns especializados (_stackoverflow_, _slack_, _mailing lists_) e entrar em contato com suporte de outras empresas (_Red Hat_, _Amazon_ e etc)
- Conversação: Com certeza te abrirá mais portas de emprego, no Brasil, no exterior ou em _Home Office_.

Se ainda estiver cético, nesse pequeno trecho que leu, foram 9 palavras em inglês.

**2 - TI é tão vasto quanto medicina**

Redes, middleware, analise de requisitos, DBA, AD, Ops, QA, Linux, Front end, back end, Java, Ruby, governança ...

Não se prenda apenas aos mais famosos, suporte e desenvolvimento (não há nenhum problema com esses dois, claro), experimente um pouco de tudo, identifique-se com algum e se especialize.

**3 - TI não é uma ciência exata**

A afirmação parece absurda, mas quem ficou horas tentando resolver algum problema sem nenhum - aparente - erro lógico, sabe do que estou falando. Isso vai causar frustração em alguns casos, mas o ponto principal aqui é saber decidir quando descobrir a causa do problema é mais importante do que de fato resolvê-lo.

**4 - Use o tutorial, mas leia a documentação**

- &apos;como instalar o git&apos; : 3.020.00 resultados no google
- &apos;CRUD no php&apos; : 7.530.000 resultados no google
- &apos;Configurar NGINX&apos; : 355.000 resultados no google

Esses tutoriais (how to) são úteis, mas entender para que serve e como funciona é essencial quando precisar consertar algo ou fazer uma melhoria.

**5 - Não tenha medo**

Quando eu comecei em TI, tinha medo de instalar o Linux e não saber configurar ou resolver um problema. Tinha medo de tentar fazer algo e errar. É clichê, largamente difundido e estudado, papo de coach, eu sei, mas errar é essencial para o aprendizado.

Hoje quando instalo ou configuro um sistema, quando crio uma pipeline, um script ou executo qualquer outra coisa e funciona na primeira tentativa, fico com uma pulga atrás da orelha achando que fiz algo errado e o problema só vai aparecer no futuro (e isso é bom pois me faz revisar tudo que fiz).

O medo sempre vai aparecer diante do novo, do inesperado e nesses momento eu penso em uma frase que escutei de um colega de trabalho alguns anos atrás:

&gt; Não sei fazer, mas se tiver tempo, posso aprender.

OBS: Se estiver fazendo algo com grande possibilidade de erro, dê preferência ao ambiente de desenvolvimento, ok?

**6 - TI é uma ferramenta, use-a.**

Passe uma semana criando um código para automatizar uma tarefa, mas não gaste 2 dias fazendo essa mesma tarefa manualmente. O tempo gasto a mais é facilmente compensado pelo que se aprendeu e pela possibilidade de executar essa mesma tarefa no futuro.

&lt;Aside type={&apos;positive&apos;} title={&apos;Muito obrigado por ler!&apos;}&gt;
  Embora eu escreva isso para mim mesmo, também é ótimo se ajudar outras
  pessoas! Então, obrigado por ler até o fim e espero ter ajudado você um pouco.
&lt;/Aside&gt;
</content:encoded>
            <author>
                <name>yuricunha</name>
                <email>hidden</email>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Conselhos que eu gostaria de ter ouvido quando comecei na tecnologia.]]></title>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">Conselhos que eu gostaria de ter ouvido quando comecei na tecnologia.</guid>
            <id>https://localhost:3000/blogs/conselhos-que-eu-gostaria-de-ter-ouvido-quando-comecei-na-tecnologia</id>
            <updated>2022-07-12</updated>
            <description>As coisas não funcionam bem assim.</description>
            <image>/static/images/blog/conselhos-que-eu-gostaria-de-ter-ouvido-quando-comecei-na-tecnologia/banner.png</image>
            <content:encoded>
&lt;Image
  alt={&apos;A procura por emprego pode ser incrivelmente frustrante.&apos;}
  src={
    &apos;/static/images/blog/conselhos-que-eu-gostaria-de-ter-ouvido-quando-comecei-na-tecnologia/banner.png&apos;
  }
  width={1905 / 2}
  height={957 / 2}
  layout=&quot;responsive&quot;
  blurDataURL={
    &apos;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAQAAAACCAIAAADwyuo0AAAACXBIWXMAAA7EAAAOxAGVKw4bAAAAIklEQVQImWNgYBDnFZCxsfc0tvJkCI/O+vP/f0tdhZK8CgBLPAfARKUieAAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==&apos;
  }
  placeholder=&quot;blur&quot;
/&gt;

**1 — A prática leva à perfeição.**&lt;br /&gt;
Não posso detalhar mais do que isso.

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

**2 — Não fique desapontado se vir códigos, sites e aplicativos que parecem bem complicados.**&lt;br /&gt;
Acredite, aqueles que elaboraram aplicativos como Instagram, WhatsApp ou Facebook praticaram décadas, talvez décadas, para elaborar esses aplicativos.&lt;br /&gt;
Você precisa de tempo. A diferença entre um mestre e um iniciante é o tempo. Afinal, o tempo traz a prática, e a experiência.

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

**3 — Você precisa de uma boa equipe.**&lt;br /&gt;
Uma boa equipe irá inspirá-lo e empurrá-lo para além dos seus limites. Claro que, uma boa equipe não se limita a trabalho, mas, amigos, colegas de faculdade, classe, e por ai vai.

&lt;br /&gt;

**4 — Escreva códigos claros e legíveis.**&lt;br /&gt;
Escrever códigos legíveis o ajudará a ler seus próprios códigos depois de um certo tempo e permitirá que outros programadores saibam o que você fez.

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

**5 — A sintaxe deve ser escrita com o máximo de concentração.**&lt;br /&gt;
Porque, um pequeno erro de sintaxe pode gerar muitos problemas, como esquecer um ponto e vírgula ou escrever _&lt;code&gt;`fuction()`&lt;/code&gt;_ em vez de _&lt;code&gt;`function()`&lt;/code&gt;_ — e, às vezes isso dói no coração.

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

**6 — Escreva nomes simples e com significado.**&lt;br /&gt;
Isso até parece vago, mas, já pensou se uma variável ou função tem um nome nada a ver com nada?!

_&lt;code&gt;`var textoMuitoLouco = 1 + 1`&lt;/code&gt;_

Agora, se eu quiser usar essa váriavel, mas ela não tem nada a ver com o valor armazenado, lascou-se.

Ah, lembre-se que existem algumas convenções que você pode usar. Eu particularmente prefiro usar o **camelCase**

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

**7 — Programar não é tão complexo.**&lt;br /&gt;
Não existe um problema tão grande na programação, o que sempre existe, é um conjunto de pequenos problemas que formam esse grande problema, e, o maior problema, é que as pessoas parecem ter vergonha de pesquisar — ou perguntar nos fóruns.

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

**8 — Leia Livros e e-livros (e-books).**&lt;br /&gt;
Leia muitos livros, os livros sempre foram os melhores recursos para aprender qualquer coisa, fora que vão te ajudar muito na lógica e paciência.

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

**9 — Você não está entediado, apenas não está motivado.**&lt;br /&gt;
Não pense que você está entediado enquanto programa. A amarga verdade é que você não está entediado, apenas não está motivado.

Lembro-me de quando eu ia elaborar algum site ou estruturar um banco de dados, e do nada eu parava e fica meio &quot;meh, que chato&quot;. Mas, eu só estava desmotivado, porém, quando eu fazia algo que nem eu mesmo imagina que conseguiria, ficava sorrindo feito um bobo, com sorriso de orelha a orelha.

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

**10 — Nem sempre acredite em Youtubers.**&lt;br /&gt;
É sério! Nem sempre acredite em Youtubers, dizendo que as 10 melhores linguagens de programação para aprender em 2022 são aquelas que eles dizem, porque às vezes, Cobol vem em primeiro lugar na lista deles, — não que seja errado, mas se for para programar na época dos dinossauros, eu tentaria inventar uma máquina do tempo.

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

**11 — Não se preocupe com o tempo.**&lt;br /&gt;
Não se preocupe com o tempo para aprender a programar.

Geralmente leva um tempo para dominar uma linguagem. Apenas se certifique de que você não está se desviando.

Tudo que é bom precisa de tempo, não se apresse em fazer coisas da noite para o dia.

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

**12 — Escolha uma linguagem ou o conjunto dela.**&lt;br /&gt;
Muitas pessoas têm a mania de começar a aprender Python, largar quando começou a ver às variáveis e já partir para HTML misturado com Ruby on Rails, procurando PHP… Calma lá, Einstein.&lt;br /&gt;
Primeiro, tente achar qual área da programação quer seguir, seja dbA, front-end ou UI/UX. E, quando decidir, você pode achar vários [roadmaps](https://roadmap.sh/ &apos;roadmaps&apos;) na internet, mas mesmo que prefira não seguir um [roadmaps](https://roadmap.sh/ &apos;roadmaps&apos;), veja a principal linguagem sendo usada e foque nela. E, pode ficar numa boa, porque uma linguagem vai te levar a outra que a completa (SQL 💚 Python, ops).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

**Conclusão:**&lt;br /&gt;
Como disse Elon Musk:&lt;br /&gt;

&gt; _You don’t need college to learn stuff, the value is seeing whether somebody can work hard at something._

Portanto, você precisa ter um plano para melhorar suas habilidades de codificação diariamente e não parar de aprender.

Após anos de experiência você se tornará um especialista.

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

**Bônus:**

Recomendarei um ótimo livro, para pessoas que decidiram começar a aprender a programar por conta própria.

O conteúdo é apresentado de concisamente em etapas que gradualmente se complementam de uma forma que permite que você acompanhe sem problemas.

&lt;br /&gt;

**Clique no link abaixo e adquira sua cópia:**&lt;br /&gt;
[The Self-Taught Programmer: The Definitive Guide to Programming Professionally](https://amzn.to/2HKwDRZ &apos;The Self-Taught Programmer: The Definitive Guide to Programming Professionally&apos;)

&lt;Aside type={&apos;positive&apos;} title={&apos;Muito obrigado por ler!&apos;}&gt;
  Embora eu escreva isso para mim mesmo, também é ótimo se ajudar outras
  pessoas! Então, obrigado por ler até o fim e espero ter ajudado você um pouco.
&lt;/Aside&gt;
</content:encoded>
            <author>
                <name>yuricunha</name>
                <email>hidden</email>
            </author>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>